See them tumbling down
Pledging their love to the ground
在西部有一个家伙
Way out West there was this fella.
我正要说关于他的故事
Fella I wanna tell you about.
他叫杰弗里.李波斯基
Fella by the name of Jeff Lebowski.
至少那是他亲爱的 父母给他的
ast that was the handle that his loving parents gave him.
然而他却不太喜欢
But he never had much use for it himself.
这个李波斯基 称自己为"酷哥"
This Lebowski, he called himself the Dude.
"酷哥"
Now Dude,
是在我家乡里 没人会用的称呼
that's a name no one would self-apply where I come from.
然而关于这个 酷哥的传奇却很多虽然对我没多大意义
But then there was a lot about the Dude that didn't make a whole lot of sense to me,
他居住的地方
and a lot about where he lived likewise.
也是光怪陆离
Drifting along with the tumbling tumbleweeds
但这也许是我觉得
But then again,maybe that's why I found the place so darned interesting.
那地方很有趣的原因
I know when night has gone That a new world's born at dawn
人们称洛杉矶为天使之城
They call Los Angeles the City of Angels.
我倒没见到什么天使
I didn't find it to be that, exactly.
但那里还是有一些好人的
But I'll allow there are some nice folks there.
因为我没去过伦敦
Course, I can't say I seen London,
也没到过法国
and I never been to France,
也没见过传说中的内衣女王
and I ain't never seen no queen in her damned undies, as the fella says.
但我告诉你
But I'll tell you what,
在了解洛杉矶之后并听了我即将说的 故事之后
after seeing Los Angeles and this here story I'm about to unfold,
你会觉得此事的悲惨无奈也是别处少见
well, I guess I've seen something
若我能把这事说下来
every bit as stupefying as you can see in any of those other places,
用英语
and in English, too.
便是死也无憾了
So I can die with a smile on my face
也不会再怨天尤人了
without feeling like the good Lord gypped me.
我将要讲述的 这个故事...
Now, this here story I'm about to unfold
发生在90年代早期
took place back in the early '90,
大概在我国与伊拉克 发生冲突的时候
just about the time of our conflict with Saddam and the lraqis.
我提起这些 是因为一个人...
I only mention it 'cause sometimes there's a man...
我不会说一个英雄
I won't say a hero.
因为英雄是什么呢?
'Cause what's a hero?
那时候有一个人...
But sometimes there's a man...
这里说的就是酷哥
And I'm talking about the Dude here.
那个人...
Sometimes there's a man...
在那个时代 那个地方
Well, he's the man for his time and place.
他适得其所的活着
He fits right in there.
就是这个洛城酷哥
And that's the Dude in Los Angeles.
即使他是个懒惰的人...
And even if he is a lazy man,
酷哥很可能是...
and the Dude was most certainly that,
洛杉矶最懒的人
quite possibly the laziest in Los Angeles county,
在世界懒人排行榜的 位置也一定很高
which would place him high in the running for laziest worldwide.
那时候有一个男人
But sometimes there's a man...
那时候这个男人...
Sometimes there's a man...
我的思路断开了
Well, I lost my train of thought here.
不管怎样
But...
我对他的介绍已经足够了
Hell, I done introduced him enough.
一次集体的行动
BUSH ON TV: ...with them all for a collective action.
这不会停止
This will not stand.
这不会停止 对科威特的侵略
This will not stand, this aggression against Kuwait.
Here on the range I belong
Drifting along
With the tumbling
Tumbleweeds
钱在哪里 李波斯基?
Where's the money, Lebowski?
我要那些钱 李波斯基
I want that money, Lebowski.
邦妮说你非常富有的
Bunny says you're good for it.
钱在哪里 李波斯基?
Where's the money, Lebowski?
钱到底在哪里 混蛋?!
Where's the fucking money, shithead?
在哪里了...我找一下
It's down there somewhere. Let me take another look.
别耍花招!
Don't fuck with us.
你老婆欠了 杰奇 特里赫姆的钱
Your wife owes money to Jackie Treehorn,
就是你欠了 杰奇 特里赫姆的钱
that means you owe money to Jackie Treehorn.
赖债不还就要吃苦头 李波斯基
Ever thus to deadbeats, Lebowski.
不要...
No, don't do...
别在我地毯上
Not on the rug, man. MAN: See?
看到了吗 李波斯基? 看到了吗?
See what happens, Lebowski? You see what happens?
没人会叫我李波斯基 你们找错人了
Nobody calls me Lebowski. You got the wrong guy.
我是酷哥
I'm the Dude, man.
你的名字是李波斯基
Your name's Lebowski, Lebowski.
你老婆叫邦妮
Your wife is Bunny.
我老婆邦妮?
My wife? Bunny?
你看到我手指上 有结婚戒指吗?
Do you see a wedding ring on my finger?
这地方像是 结了婚的人住的吗?
Does this place look like I'm fucking married?
马桶的坐板放起来了
The toilet seat's up, man!
这是什么?
What the fuck is this?
显然你不打高尔夫
Obviously you're not a golfer.
吴?
Woo? Yeah.
怎么了?那家伙像是个富翁吗?
Isn't this guy supposed to be a millionaire?
操!
Fuck.
你说呢?
Yeah. What do you think?
他样子像个失败者
He looks like a fucking loser.
起码我有教养
Hey, at least I'm housebroken.
浪费时间!
Fucking time-waster.
谢了 混蛋
Thanks a lot, asshole.
La-la-la, la-la-la, la-la-la
La-la-la, la, la, la, la
La-la-la, la, la, la-la la-la
la, la-la
La-la-la
La-la-la, la-la-la
La-la, la-la
The man in me will do
Nearly any task
And as for compensation
There's little he would ask
Take a woman like you
To get through
To the man in me
Storm clouds are raging
All around my door
I think to myself
I might not take it anymore
Take a woman like your kind
To find the man in me
But, oh
What a wonderful feeling
Just to know that you are near
Sets my heart a-reeling
From my toes
Up to my ears
The man in me will hide sometimes
To keep from being seen
But that's just because he doesn't want
To turn into some machine
Take a woman like you
To get through
To the man in me
我今晚手风很顺啊 记分吧 酷哥
I'm throwing rocks tonight. Mark it, Dude.
那是很有价值的地毯 那是...
I'm telling you, this was a valued rug. This was a...
那地毯和我的屋子很搭配
Yeah, man. It really tied the room together.
那是很有价值的...
This was a valued...
什么东西跟你房间很搭配 酷哥? 我的地毯
What tied the room together, Dude? My rug.
你刚才有听酷哥 讲故事吗 唐尼?
Were you listening to the Dude's story, Donny?
什么? 沃尔特
What? Walter.
你刚才有 听酷哥讲故事吗?
Were you listening to the Dude's story? I was bowling.
我刚在打保龄球啊 那你就什么 都不了解 唐尼
So you have no frame of reference here, Donny.
你就像一个中途 出来打岔的...
You're like a child who wanders into the middle of a movie and wants to know...
沃尔特 你想说明什么? 听我说 酷哥...
Walter, what's the point, man? There's no reason, here's my point, Dude.
没有任何理由...
There's no fucking reason why these two...
是啊 沃尔特 你想说明什么?
Yeah, Walter, what's your point?
沃尔特 你想说明什么
Walter, what is the...
听着 很明显到底是谁没搞清楚
Look, we all know who is at fault here.
你到底在说什么鬼话?
What the fuck are you talking about? Huh?
你...我...
No, what the fuck are you... I'm not...
我们在说 讨债打错人的事情 酷哥
We're talking about unchecked aggression here, Dude.
他到底在说什么鬼话?
What the fuck is he talking about? My rug.
我的地毯 算了 唐尼 歇一边去
Forget it, Donny!You're out of your element!
沃尔特 那个中国仔 在我地毯上撒尿
Walter, the Chinaman who peed on my rug,
但我找不着他赔偿我
I can't go give him a bill!
你到底在说什么?
So what the fuck are you talking about?
What the fuck are you talking about?
我们讨论的不是 那个中国仔 酷哥
The Chinaman is not the issue here, Dude!
我在说忍耐的底限 酷哥
I'm talking about drawing a line in the sand, Dude.
如果越过了就要...
Across this line you do not...
还有 酷哥 叫他中国仔不太合适
Also, Dude, "Chinaman" is not the preferred nomenclature.
应该叫亚裔美国人
Asian-American, please.
沃尔特 这些人可不是那些修铁路的人
Walter, this isn't a guy who built the railroads here. This is a guy...
那家伙...你在说什么啊
What the fuck are you...
沃尔特 他在我的 地毯上撒尿
Walter, he peed on my rug!He peed on the Dude's rug.
唐尼 够了
Donny, you're out of your element.
酷哥 那中国仔不是重点所在
Dude, the Chinaman is not the issue here.
那谁...杰弗里.李波斯基
So, who... Jeff Lebowski.
另一个杰弗里.李波斯基 百万富翁
The other Jeffrey Lebowski. The millionaire.
那真的很有意思
That's fucking interesting, man. That's fucking interesting.
他有财有势
Plus, he has the wealth, obviously, and the resources,
所以没有任何理由...
so that there's no reason, there's no fucking reason
他老婆会出来玩 并欠了债
why his wife should go out and owe money all over town,
然后那些人来你家 在你的地毯上撒尿!
and then they come and they pee on your fucking rug!
- 我说错了吗? - 不
- Am I wrong? - No.
我错了么? 但是...
Am I wrong? Yeah, but...
那么...
Okay then.
那地毯和你家屋子很搭 对吧?
That rug really tied the room together, did it not?
当然了!那个家伙还在上面撒尿
Fucking A. And this guy peed on it.
唐尼
Donny, please.
我能找到那个
You know, this is the fucking guy...
该死的李波斯基
I could find this fucking Lebowski guy.
他叫李波斯基? 你不就是这个名字么 酷哥
His name is Lebowski? That's your name, Dude.
他应该赔偿我的地毯
This is the guy who should compensate me for the fucking rug.
他老婆出来玩 到处欠债 还让人在我的 地毯上撒尿?
His wife goes out and owes money all over town, and they pee on my rug?
他们在你的地毯上撒尿
They pee on your fucking rug?
没错 是啊 酷哥
Peed on my fucking rug. That's right, Dude.
他们在你的地毯上撒尿
They peed on your fucking rug.
这里就是书房
This is the study.
有各种各样的奖状...
As you can see, the various commendations, awards...
"杰弗里.李波斯基" 荣誉学位等等
"Jeffrey Lebowski." ...citations, honorary degrees, et cetera.
非常厉害 请随便查看
Very impressive. Oh, please feel free to inspect them.
我不是那么...
Oh. No, I'm not really... Oh, please. Please.
有请 那是帕萨里那城的钥匙
That is the key to the city of Pasadena,
两年前李波斯基先生 成为那里的杰出市民
which Mr. Lebowski received two years ago in recognition of his various civic...
那是洛杉矶商会的 商业成就奖
Oh!That's the Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce Business Achiever Award,
并不是每年都颁发的
which is given... Oh, not necessarily given every year.
那是
Hey, is this...
他和南茜 (里根夫人)的合照?
Given only when there's a worthy somebody...Is this him with Nancy?
是的 那就是李波斯基 先生和第一夫人...
Yes, indeed, that is Mr. Lebowski with the first lady, yes.
在左边的就是 李波斯基?
It was taken when Mrs. Reagan...That's Lebowski on the left there?
当然了 李波斯基 先生就在左边 他是个跛子
Of course. Mr. Lebowski, on the left... So he's a...
他是残疾人?
You know, a handicapped kind of guy?
李波斯基先生 是伤残人士
Mr. Lebowski is disabled, yes.
那是在里根 任职总统时拍的照片
This picture was taken when Mrs. Reagan was first lady of the nation.
嗯 嗯
Yes, yes.
并不是加州州长那时候
Not of California. Good shot.
约翰教皇他曾经和总统私下会面
In fact, he met privately with the President,
但不幸的是当时没足够的时间拍照
though, unfortunately, there wasn't enough time for a photo opportunity.
南茜是个不错的女人
Oh, Nancy's pretty good. Oh, wonderful woman.
是啊 非常好
We were very happy to... These are...
这些是...李波斯基先生的子女
Oh, those are Mr. Lebowski's children, so to speak.
同父异母的?
Different mothers, huh?
很多种族 十分博爱啊
No, they're not... Racially, he's pretty cool?
他们并非他的子女
They're not literally his children.
他们是李波斯基先生的义子女
They're the Little Lebowski Urban Achievers,
他们缺乏接受...
inner city children of promise, but without the necessary means for...
高等教育的条件
Necessary means for a higher education,
于是李波斯基先生 资助他们上大学
so Mr. Lebowski is committed to sending all of them to college.
不好意思
Excuse me. Oh, geez.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
很好啊 还有多一个位子吗? 一个...
Far out. Think he's got room for one more? One... Oh.
你还没上过大学
You never went to college.
不好意思
Please, don't touch that. Oh, yeah, yeah. No, I did,
我上过的 但是...
but, you know, I spent most of my time
我大部分时间都跑到其他建筑里瞎逛了
occupying various administration buildings,
抽大麻...
smoking a lot of Thai stick,
溜进军营还有打保龄
breaking into the ROTC and bowling.
告诉你吧 布兰特 我就是混过来的
Tell you the truth, Brandt, I don't remember most of it.
你也叫李波斯基 我也叫李波斯基
Okay, sir. You're a Lebowski, I'm a Lebowski.
非常好
That's terrific.
但我现在很忙 我想你也应该是
But I am very busy, as I imagine you are.
我能帮你什么吗?
What can I do for you, sir?
先生...我有一块地毯
Well, sir, it's this rug I have.
和我家很搭调的地毯
It really tied the room together.
你在电话上告诉布兰特 他也告诉了我
You told Brandt on the phone. He told me.
这与我有什么关系?
Where do I fit in?
那两个男人要找的是你
Well, they were looking for you, these two guys.
你知道...我再说一次
You know, they... I'll say it again.
这些 布兰特已经告诉我了
You told Brandt on the phone. He told me.
我知道发生了什么事情
I know what happened. Yes, yes.
你知道他们想在 我的地毯上撒尿?
Oh, so you know that they were trying to piss on your rug.
请问我在那地毯上撒尿了吗?
Did I urinate on your rug?
你是问是否你亲自尿上面了?
You mean, did you personally come and pee on my rug?
你会说英语吗?
Hello!Do you speak English, sir?
Parla usted English?
我再问一次 我在 那地毯上撒尿了吗?
I'll ask you again. Did I urinate on your rug?
没有 是那个叫吴的人做的
No. Like I said, Woo peed on my rug.
我只想明白这个
I just want to understand this, sir.
如果谁的地毯被人撒尿了
Every time a rug is micturated upon in this fair city,
我也要赔偿吗?
I have to compensate the person?
你看 我不是想来这里敲诈的
Come on, man. I'm not trying to scam anybody here.
我只是...
You know, I'm just...
你想找一些施舍就像其他的人...
You're just looking for a handout like every other...
你有工作吗 李波斯基先生?
Are you employed, Mr. Lebowski?
等一等 让我解释一下
Wait. Let me explain something to you.
我不是李波斯基
I am not Mr. Lebowski.
先生 你才是 我是酷哥
You're Mr. Lebowski. I'm the Dude.
别人都这样叫我
So that's what you call me. You know? That or His Dudeness,
就叫我酷哥吧
or Duder or, you know,
或者叫我酷哥斯 或者酷哥儿 随便什么样
El Duderino, if you're not into the whole brevity thing.
你有工作吗 先生?
Are you employed, sir?
工作?
Employed?
你不会穿成 这样去工作吧?
You don't go out looking for a job dressed like that, do you? On a weekday?
这是...
Is this a...
今天星期几了? 我有工作的 先生
What day is this? Well, I do work, sir.
- 如果你不介意 - 我介意的 酷哥介意
- So, if you don't mind... - No, I do mind. The Dude minds.
这是无法接受的
This will not stand, you know.
这绝对无法接受
This aggression will not stand, man.
你妻子欠了...
I mean, your wife owes money...
我妻子不是讨论的重点所在!
My wife is not the issue here!
我希望我妻子总有一天 学会使用她的零花钱
I hope that someday my wife will learn to live on her allowance,
那是足够的
which is ample.
如果她觉得不够 那也是她的问题 不是我的问题
But if she does not, that is her problem, not mine,
就像那地毯 是你的问题一样
just as the rug is your problem.
每个混混的命运 也是他自己的责任
Just as every bum's lot in life is his own responsibility,
不能去埋怨别人
regardless of who he chooses to blame.
我失去了双腿 也不会埋怨谁
I didn't blame anyone for the loss of my legs.
我在韩战的时候失去的
Some Chinaman took them from me in Korea.
但我后来也成功了
But I went out and achieved anyway.
我不能解决你的问题 先生 只有你可以
I cannot solve your problems, sir. Only you can.
去他妈的
Well, fuck it. Oh, fuck it.
对 去他妈的 那是你对所有事情的回答
Yes, that's your answer. That's your answer to everything.
纹在前额上吧
Tattoo it on your forehead!
你可别想翻身了 李波斯基先生!
Your revolution is over, Mr. Lebowski!
哀悼吧!你这种游手好闲的人!
Condolences!The bums lost!
我给你的建议是 像你父母那样
My advice to you is to do what your parents did!
找份工作吧!
Get a job, sir!
游手好闲的总是失败者!
The bums will always lose!
你听到吗 姓李的?!
Do you hear me, Lebowski?
游手好闲的总是失败者!
The bums will always lose.
你的会见怎样了 李波斯基先生?
How was your meeting, Mr. Lebowski?
好
Okay.
老先生说我可以拿走 这里任何一块地毯
The old man told me to take any rug in the house.
非常好
Well, enjoy.
也许我们会再见的 酷哥
And perhaps we'll see you again sometime, Dude.
是啊
Yeah, sure.
如果将来我经过这附近一定来你这借厕所 对了...
If I'm in the neighborhood, you know,
我要上洗手间
and I need to use the john.
吹
Blow on them. Huh?
吹啊
Go ahead. Blow.
你要我吹?
You want me to blow on your toes?
因为我自己吹不到
I can't blow that far.
你肯定他不会介意吗?
Are you sure he won't mind?
他什么也不介意 他是一个虚无主义者
Uli doesn't care about anything. He's a nihilist.
那真累啊
Oh, that must be exhausting.
你没有吹啊
You're not blowing.
他是我们的客人 李波斯基太太
Our guest has to be getting along, Mrs. Lebowski.
你就是邦妮
You're Bunny.
给我一千块我就帮你舔
I'll suck your cock for $1 ,000.
美妙的女人啊
Wonderful woman.
她对性的开放 多么令人激赏呀!
We're all very fond of her. Very free-spirited.
布兰特不能观看 否则他就要给1百
Brandt can't watch though, or he has to pay $100.
太不可思议了
That's marvelous.
我要去找一个提款机
I'm just gonna go find a cash machine.
今晚我手风很顺
I'm slamming them tonight!
你们倒霉了
You guys are dead in the water.
走着瞧吧 唐尼!
All right!Way to go, Donny!
有志者事竟成
"lf you will it, it is no dream."
你迟到20分钟了 老兄 那是什么鬼东西?
Fucking 20 minutes late, man. What the fuck is that?
提奥多尔 何素的著作
Theodore Herzl. Huh?
"犹太人的国家" 酷哥 有志者事竟成
State of lsrael. If you will it, Dude, it is no dream.
你在说什么鬼话?
What the fuck are you talking about, man?
我问的是笼子里面有什么
The carrier. What's in the fucking carrier? Huh?
那是辛迪雅的狗 应该是波美拉尼亚狗
Oh!Cynthia's dog. Think it's a Pomeranian.
我不能把它留在家里不然它会吃家具
Can't leave him home alone or he eats the furniture.
辛迪雅和马迪去 夏威夷的时候我要看着它
I'm watching it while Cynthia and Marty Ackerman are in Hawaii.
你带着那讨厌的 狗来打保龄?
You brought a fucking Pomeranian bowling?
带来打保龄?
What do you mean, brought it bowling?
我不用给它租鞋子 我也不用给它买啤酒
I didn't rent it shoes. I'm not buying it a fucking beer.
他也不能顶替你个衰人 酷哥
He's not taking your fucking turn, Dude.
如果我那该死的前妻 在和他男友去玩的时候
Man, if my fucking ex-wife asked me to take care of her fucking dog
叫我帮她看着小狗
while she and her boyfriend went to Honolulu,
我一定会叫她见鬼去吧 为什么不能带上飞机?
I'd tell her to go fuck herself. Why can't she board it?
酷哥 首先你没有前妻
First of all, Dude, you don't have an ex.
其次 这是一只名犬
Secondly, this is a fucking show dog with fucking papers.
不能带上飞机 它会发脾气的 毛也会掉下来
You can't board it. It gets upset. its hair falls out.
沃尔特...该死的名犬
Walter... Fucking dog has fucking papers.
越线了!
Over the line!Huh?
不好意思 烟仔 你的脚越线了
I'm sorry, Smokey. You were over the line. That's a foul.
那是犯规的 胡说 记一个8分 酷哥
Bullshit. Mark it eight, Dude.
记零分 下一轮
Excuse me. Mark it zero. Next frame.
胡说 沃尔特  记一个8分 酷哥
Bullshit, Walter. Mark it eight, Dude.
烟仔 这里不是 越南 现在是打保龄
Smokey, this is not Nam. This is bowling. There are rules.
凡事都讲规则 沃尔特 只是...算了吧 烟仔是哥们儿
Hey, Walter, come on. Hey, man, it's Smokey.
他的脚越线了
So his toe slipped over a little, you know.
只是游戏而已 这是计分赛 决定
It's just a game, man. This is a league game.
谁进入下一次巡回赛
This determines who enters the next round robin.
- 我有错吗?- 你是没错 但我也没有...
- Am I wrong? - Yeah, but I wasn't...
我错了吗? 没错 但我得8分也没错
Am I wrong? Yeah, but I wasn't over.
给我记分表 酷哥 我要记一个8分
Give me the marker, Dude. I'm marking an eight.
烟仔
Smokey, my friend,
你在进入一个痛苦的世界 沃尔特
you're entering a world of pain. Walter, man.
记录一个8分 你在进入一个痛苦的世界
You mark that frame an eight, you're entering a world of pain.
我不会...一个痛苦的世界
I'm not... A world of pain.
酷哥 这是你的搭档
Look, Dude, this is your partner.
这个世界变疯狂了吗?!
Has the whole world gone crazy?
这里只有我在乎规则吗?
Am I the only one around here who gives a shit about the rules?
记零分!
Mark it zero!
他们在叫警察 伙计 拿开那东西
They're calling the cops, man. Put the piece away.
- 记零分!- 沃尔特 拿开那东西
- Mark it zero!- Walter, put the piece away.
沃尔特 你以为我在开玩笑吗?
Walter. You think I'm fucking around here?
记零分!
Mark it zero!
好了 一个零分
All right. It's fucking zero.
你高兴了吗 疯子?
You happy, you crazy fuck?
这是计分
It's a league game, Smokey.
你不能这样做
You can't do that, man.
这些人和我一样 是和平主义者
These guys, you know, they're like me, they're pacifists.
烟仔是一个 拒绝兵役的人
Smokey was a conscientious objector.
酷哥 你知道我曾经 是和平主义者
You know, Dude, I myself dabbled in pacifism at one point.
当然不是在越南的时候
Not in Nam, of course.
你知道刚才这样他很难受
And you know he's got emotional problems, man.
超过了和平主义?
You mean, beyond pacifism?
他很脆弱 非常脆弱
He's fragile. He's very fragile.
我可不知道
I did not know that.
算了 覆水难收
Well, it's all water under the bridge.
我们一定要进入 下一次巡回赛
And we do enter the next round robin.
- 我有错吗? - 不 你没错
- Am I wrong? - No, you're not wrong.
- 我有错吗? - 你没错 沃尔特
- Am I wrong? - You're not wrong, Walter.
你只是个混蛋!
You're just an asshole.
那好吧
Okay then.
我们下周就要对 昆提那和奥布赖恩
Play Quintana and O'Brien next week.
他们应该很容易对付
They should be pushovers.
你能不能...
Man, would you just...
放轻松 伙计
Just take it easy, man.
那是你对所有 问题的回答 酷哥
You know, that's your answer for everything, Dude.
我要指出一点
Let me point out something. Pacifism is not...
看看现在伊拉克的情况
Look at our current situation with that camel fucker in Iraq.
和平主义不是 用来隐藏的
Pacifism is not something to hide behind.
放轻松 伙计
Just take it easy, man.
我非常冷静 酷哥
I'm perfectly calm, Dude.
挥舞着手枪也算是吗? 比你更冷静
Yeah, waving the fucking gun around? Calmer than you are.
你别那么冲动好吗?
Will you just take it easy?
比你更冷静
Calmer than you are.
酷哥 这是烟仔
Dude, this is Smokey.
我不想在这件 事情上搞僵了
Look, I don't wanna be a hard-on about this,
我知道那不是你的错
and I know it wasn't your fault,
但我觉得应该告诉你
but I just thought it was fair to tell you
吉尔伯特和我会将 这个递交给赛会
that Gilbert and I will be submitting this to the league
并要求他们取消 这一轮的赛事
and asking them to set aside the round.
也许会将罚分记给我们
I don't know, maybe forfeit it to us.
我想只是一个警告
So, like I say, just thought, you know, fair warning.
告诉沃尔特
Tell Walter.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
李波斯基先生 我是布兰特...
Mr. Lebowski, this is Brandt at...
我在李波斯基 先生的办公室
Well, at Mr. Lebowski's office.
请尽快回电
Please call us as soon as it's convenient.
李波斯基先生 我是
Mr. Lebowski, this is Mel Zelnicker
南部保龄球赛会的比尔
of the Southern Cal Bowling League.
我刚收到一份 非正式的报告 你的一位队员 沃尔特 索布查克...
I just got an informal report that a member of your team, a Walter Sobchak,
在计分的 时候出示枪械
drew a firearm during league play.
如果情况属实
If this is true, of course,
此行为违反了
it contravenes a number of the league's bylaws
计分的规则...
and also article 27 of the league...
- 酷哥 - 你好啊 蒙迪
- Dude. - Hey, Marty.
酷哥 我参加了...
Dude, I finally got...
舞蹈比赛
I got the venue I wanted.
我将表演5人舞蹈
I'm performing my dance quintet, you know, my cycle,
周二晚上在杰克森 喷泉剧院举行
at Crane Jackson's Fountain Street Theater on Tuesday night.
希望你能到场给我打气
And, well, I'd love it if you came and gave me notes.
我会去的 伙计
I'll be there, man.
酷哥...明天已经10号了
Dude, tomorrow's already the tenth.
是啊
Far out.
哦 对了
Oh. Oh, all right. Okay.
把房租塞进我门口就行了
Just slip the rent under my door.serious infraction and examine your standing.
谢谢
Thank you.
李波斯基先生 又是我布兰特
Mr. Lebowski, Brandt again.
请尽快回复我们我会派轿车来接你
Please do call us as soon as you get in and I'll send the limo.
希望你不会拒绝 因为那地毯的事情...
I hope you're not avoiding this call because of the rug,
我可以保证 绝对不是问题
which I assure you is not a problem.
我们需要你的帮忙
We need your help, and...
我们非常想见到你 谢谢你 我是布兰特
Well, we would very much like to see you. Thank you. It's Brandt.
我们有个坏消息
We've had some terrible news.
李波斯基先生 将自己隔离在西边房
Mr. Lebowski's in seclusion in the west wing.
李波斯基先生
Mr. Lebowski.
真有意思
Funny.
回顾我一生的成就
I can look back on a life of achievement,
迎接过无数挑战
challenges met,
打败过无数对手
competitors bested,
克服过无数障碍
obstacles overcome.
我比大多数男人 有更多的成就
I've accomplished more than most men
而且没有使用到双脚
and without the use of my legs.
什么样可称为男人 李波斯基先生?
What makes a man, Mr. Lebowski?
叫我"酷哥"
Dude. Huh?
我不知道 先生
Oh, I don't know, sir.
做好准备 做正确的事情
Is it being prepared to do the right thing,
无论以何种代价?
whatever the cost?
但这样便可称为男人吗?
Isn't that what makes a man?
还要有一对睾丸
Sure, that and a pair of testicles.
真会开玩笑
You're joking,
但是 也许你是对的
but perhaps you're right.
介意我抽烟吗?
You mind if I do a Jay?
邦妮...
Bunny.
什么?
Excuse me?
邦妮 李波斯基
Bunny Lebowski.
她是我生命中的烛火
She is the light of my life.
你对我流泪感到惊讶吗?
Are you surprised at my tears, sir?
当然了
Oh, fucking A.
坚强的男人也会流泪
Strong men also cry.
今天早上我收到这个传真
I received this fax this morning.
你可以看到 这是要求赎金的
As you can see, it is a ransom note.
"邦妮在我们手上"
"We have Bunny."
写自一些不敢 公平较量的人之手
Written by men who were unable to achieve on a level field of play.
"筹集一百万美金"
"Gather $1 million..."
"没有记录的 不连续的20元纸币"
Cowards!"...in unmarked, nonconsecutive 20."
懦夫!"等待指示"
Weaklings!"Await instructions."
混混!"这不是开玩笑的"
Bums!"No funny stuff."
无赖
Bummer. Huh?
无赖 那是个无赖
This is a bummer, man. That's... That's a bummer.
布兰特会给你讲解细节
Brandt will fill you in on the details.
李波斯基先生将给 送赎金的人一份大方的报酬
Mr. Lebowski is prepared to make a generous offer to you to act as courier
现在我们只等他们的指示
once we get instructions for the money.
为什么找我?
Why me, man?
他相信那些 污染你地毯的人...和绑架的歹徒是一伙的
He believes the culprits might be the very people who soiled your rug
而你在此事中的 位置很特别
and you are in a unique position to confirm or disconfirm that suspicion.
他认为是那撒尿的 家伙干的?
He thinks the carpet pissers did this?
酷哥 我们就是不知道
Well, Dude, we just don't know.
"耶稣"
Welcome to the Hotel California
Such a lovely place
该死的昆提那
Fucking Quintana.
那家伙很棒哦
That creep can roll, man.
没错 但他是个 变态 酷哥
Yeah, but he's a pervert, Dude. Yeah.
是啊 他是个有性侵犯 案底的家伙
No, he's a sex offender with a record.
在齐诺监狱坐了6个月 因为他对一个 8岁男孩露下体
He did six months in Chino for exposing himself to an eight-year-old.
他搬去好莱坞之后他还要挨家挨户地告诉别人
When he moved to Hollywood, he had to go door-to-door
他是个鸡奸者
to tell everyone he was a pederast.
- 鸡奸者是什么 沃尔特? - 闭嘴 唐尼
- What's a pederast, Walter? - Shut the fuck up, Donny.
他们给你多少钱?
So, how much did he give you?
两万 而且我还能得到那地毯
20 grand, man. And, of course, I still get to keep the rug.
就是那举手之劳? 是啊
Just for making a hand-off? Yeah.
他们还给了酷哥一个传呼机
They gave Dude a beeper.
如果那些人传呼...如果正在打比赛呢?
So whenever these guys call... What if it's during a game?
我告诉过他们如果 在比赛当中...
Oh, I told them if it was during league play...
什么比赛当中?
What's during league play?
地球不会为你停转
Life does not stop and start at your convenience,
你这个垃圾
you miserable piece of shit.
我想...沃尔特怎么了 酷哥?
I figure... What's wrong with Walter, Dude?
好赚 又无风险
I figure it's easy money, you know. It's all pretty harmless.
她有可能叫人绑架自己
She probably kidnapped herself.
什么意思 酷哥? 在地毯上撒尿的人不会做那些事情
What do you mean, Dude? Rug-peers did not do this.
看看 一个年轻女子为了钱嫁人
Look at it. A young trophy wife marries this guy for his money.
她觉得他没给她足够的钱
She figures he isn't giving her enough, you know.
而她在城里欠了一身债
She owes money all over town.
那个该死的婊子!
That fucking bitch!
这是个骗局
It's all a goddamn fake, man.
像列宁说的那样
It's like Lenin said,
找一个可以获得好处的人 你知道...
you look for the person who will benefit and, you know...
"我是海象 "(Beatles名曲)你会...
I Am the Walrus? You know, you'll...
你知道我想说什么的 我是海象
You know what I'm trying to say. I Am the Walrus.
那该死的婊子!是啊
That fucking bitch!Oh, yeah!
"我是海象"
I Am the Walrus. That's...
闭嘴 唐尼!
Shut the fuck up, Donny!
弗拉基米尔 伊里奇 列宁!
V.l. Lenin, Vladimir llyich Ulyanov!
他在说什么鬼话?
What the fuck is he talking about?
刚才的事让他发疯了
Fucking exactly what happened to those...That makes me fucking sick!
你在乎什么 沃尔特? 那些该死的有钱人
Well, what do you care, Walter? Those rich fucks.
这件该死的事情
This whole fucking thing.
当年我没能够亲见 好哥们在泥沼中死去
I did not watch my buddies die face down in the muck
那个该死的贱货
so that this fucking strumpet,
妓女...
this fucking whore, could waltz around...
我不觉得这与 越战有什么联系
I don't see any connection with Vietnam, man.
有文字上的联系
Well, there isn't a literal connection, Dude.
不 沃尔特 没有任何联系
No, Walter, face it, there isn't any connection.
到你了
Your roll. Have it your way.
到你了 但我要说的是
Your roll. But my point is...
- 我要说的是... - 你准备好被宰了吗?
- My point is... - Are you ready to be fucked, man?
我知道你们进了半决赛
I see you rolled your way into the semis.
我的天啊
Dios mfo, man.
里奥和我会将你们干掉的
Liam and me, we're gonna fuck you up.
是吗? 那就像是...你的一厢情愿 伙计
Yeah? Well, you know, that's just like your opinion, man.
我告诉你
Let me tell you something, pendejo.
你若敢对我们掏家伙
You pull any of your crazy shit with us,
你的肉就会飞到球道上
you flash a piece out on the lanes,
我会扣动扳机
I'll take it away from you and stick it up your ass
叫你屁眼开花...打到没子弹为止
and pull the fucking trigger till it goes click.
"耶稣"...
Jesus.
你说了 伙计
You said it, man.
没人可以斗得过耶稣
Nobody fucks with the Jesus.
记得那个8岁的小男孩吧 酷哥
Eight-year-olds, Dude.
La-la-la, la-la-la, la-la-la
La-la-la, la, la, la, la
La-la, la-la
La-la-la
La-la-la, la-la-la
La-la, la-la
The man in me will do
Nearly any task
And as for compensation
There's little he would ask
Take a woman like you
To get through
To the man in me
Storm clouds are raging
All around my door
I think to myself
I might not take it anymore
Take a woman like your kind
To find the man in me
But, oh
What a wonderful feeling
Just to know
That you are near
Sets my heart a-reeling
From my toes
Up to my ears
The man in me will hide sometimes
他们80分钟前呼叫的
They called about? minutes ago.
他们想让你带钱去 开车到405公路北面
They want you to take the money, drive north on the 405.
40分钟后
They will call you on the portable phone
会有人打电话给你指示
with instructions in about 40 minutes.
只能有一个人
One person only.
他们说得很清楚 不然我就和你一起去了
They were very clear on that, or I'd go with you. One person only.
- 你的下巴怎么了? - 没什么
- What happened to yourjaw? - Oh, nothing, man.
钱在这里
Here's the money.
还有电话
And the phone.
酷哥 请你按照他们的指示
Please, Dude, follow whatever instructions they give.
好的 她的性命就在你手上
All right. Her life is in your hands.
别那样说
Man, don't say that.
李波斯基先生要我重复的 她的性命就在你手上
Mr. Lebowski asked me to repeat that, her life is in your hands.
哦 妈的
Oh, shit, man.
她的性命就在你手上 酷哥
Her life is in your hands, Dude.
完事后马上报告
Report back to us as soon as it's done.
你在搞什么? 你拿着 我开车
Where the fuck are you going, man? Take the ringer, I'll drive.
- 拿什么? - 箱子
- The what? - The ringer.
调包计 酷哥
The ringer, Dude.
他们还没来电吗? 你怎么...
What the... Have they called yet?
这是什么?
What the hell is this?
我的脏内裤 酷哥 刚想拿去洗的
My dirty undies, Dude. The laundry. The whites.
沃尔特 你带着这些来 一定有什么原因
Walter, I'm sure there's a reason you brought your dirty undies, man.
没错 酷哥 要那种重量
That's right, Dude. The weight.
那箱子不能空着
The ringer cannot look empty.
沃尔特 你想的是什么?
Walter, what the fuck are you thinking, man?
你说得对 酷哥 我应该想想...
You're right, Dude. I got to thinking.
为什么我们 只要那小小的两万
I got to thinking, why should we settle for a measly fucking 20 grand...
我们? 怎么是我们了? 你说你只是想跟我去的
We? What the fuck, "we"? You said you just wanted to come along.
酷哥 我说的是...我们手上拿着一百万的
My point, Dude, is why should we settle for 20 grand
时候为什么还想着那两万? 我错了吗?
when we can keep the entire million? Am I wrong?
是的 你错了 现在不是在玩游戏 伙计
Yes, you're wrong. This isn't a fucking game, man.
但这就是个游戏 你自己说过的
Oh, but it is a game. You said so yourself.
她绑架了自己 我说我想是...
She kidnapped herself. I said I thought...
- 我是酷哥 - 谁?
- Dude, here. - Who is this?
我是送赎金的人 你要我们怎么办?
Dude. The bagman, man. Where do you want us to go?
我们?
Us?
该死的!
Shit!
是的 我还有司机
Yeah, you know, me and the driver.
我不能一边拿着钱开车 一边讲电话...
I'm not handling the money, driving the car and talking on the phone all by my...
闭嘴!
Shut the fuck up!
酷哥 你搞砸了吗? 那是谁?
Dude, are you fucking this up? Who is that?
那是司机 我告诉过你...
That is the driver. I told you...
该死的!怎么了?
Oh, shit!What the fuck's going on?
沃尔特!怎么了?
Walter... What the fuck is going on?
他挂机了!你搞砸了!你搞砸了!
He hung up, man. You fucked it up. You fucked it up!
她的性命 在我们手上 伙计 别紧张 酷哥
Her life was in our hands, man. Easy, Dude.
我们什么也没做到 他们一定会杀了她
We're screwed now. We don't get shit. They're gonna kill her.
我们搞砸了 沃尔特 什么也没搞砸 酷哥
We're fucked, Walter. Nothing is fucked, Dude.
你现在非常不酷哥
Come on. You're being very un-Dude.
他们会再来电的 她绑架了...
They'll call back. Look, she kidnapped...
看到了吗? 什么也没搞砸 酷哥
You see? Nothing's fucked here, Dude.
什么也没搞砸 他们只是一帮业余的混蛋!
Nothing is fucked. They're a bunch of fucking amateurs.
沃尔特 先闭嘴好吗?
Walter, will you just shut the fuck up?
我在做正事的时候别捣乱
Don't say peep while I'm doing business here, man.
好吧 酷哥
Okay, Dude. Have it your way.
他们只是业余的 操
But they're amateurs. Fuck.
酷哥
Dude.
好了 我们继续 但不能再耍花样
Okay, we proceed but only if there is no funny stuff.
好的
Yeah, yeah.
不再耍花样 好了吗?
So no funny sturt Okay?
告诉我们该去哪里
Just tell me where the fuck you want us to go.
那里有个标志
That was the sign, man.
我们要做的 就是带她回来
So, all we gotta do is get her back.
不能抱怨谁
No one's in a position to complain.
小费我们留着 好极了 沃尔特
We keep the baksheesh. Yeah, terrific, Walter.
但你还没告诉我 怎样带她回来 她在哪里?
But you haven't told me how we're gonna get her back. Where is she?
那是很简单的 酷哥
That's the simple part, Dude.
我们去交换 让我把那个家伙打昏
We make the hand-off, I grab one of them and beat it out of him. Huh?
是啊 那是一个 很好的计划
That's a great plan, Walter.
沃尔特 你真是天才 如果我的理解是对的
That's fucking ingenious, if I understand it correctly.
这就像瑞士手表那样精确
It's a Swiss fucking watch.
没错 酷哥 简单即是美
That's right, Dude. The beauty of this is its simplicity.
一旦计划变得复杂 什么都会出错
Once a plan gets too complex, everything can go wrong.
如果说我学到了什么...
If there's one thing I learned in Nam...
我是酷哥
Dude.
你们将要到达一座木桥
You are coming to wooden bridge.
过桥的时候...
When you cross the bridge,
不要停车 将箱子从 左边的窗户扔出去
you throw the bag from the left window of the moving car.
你们正被监视
You're being watched.
该死的!他怎么说? 在哪里交换?
Fuck. What'd he say? Where's the hand-off?
现在没有交换了
There is no fucking hand-off, man.
我们要在那木桥上 将钱扔下去
At the wooden bridge we throw the money out of the car.
开着车将钱扔下去
We throw the money out of the moving car.
我们不能那样做 酷哥 那样会搞砸我们的计划
We can't do that, Dude. That fucks up our plan.
给他们电话 解释一下 沃尔特
Well, call them up and explain it to them, Walter.
你的计划太简单了
Your plan is so fucking simple,
我肯定他们会明白的
I'm sure they'll fucking understand it.
那就是它的美
That's the beauty of it.
木桥是吗? 我要把钱扔下去 沃尔特
Wooden bridge, huh? Throw them the money, Walter.
不能这样搞砸了
We're not fucking around, man.
酷哥 木桥就到了 快把调包的箱子给我
Okay, Dude, the bridge is coming up. Give me the ringer, chop-chop.
去你的 沃尔特 我爱你
Fuck that. Walter, I love you,
将来你迟早要面对那事实就是你是个该死的傻瓜
but sooner or later you're gonna have to face the fact you're a goddamn moron.
酷哥 没时间争论了
Okay, Dude. No time to argue. Hey, man!
那木桥 沃尔特!沃尔特!
Here's the bridge. Hey, Walter!Hey, Walter!
出去了!
Hey, Walter!Here goes the ringer!
怎么了? 酷哥 你开车
What the fuck? Okay, Dude, you're wheel.
时速保持15英里 我滚出去
Hey, man, what the fuck? At 15 mph, I roll out.
我回头将他们 其中一个收拾掉
I double back, grab one of them and beat it out of him.
- 乌兹冲锋枪 - 乌兹冲锋枪?!
- The Uzi. - Uzi.
你不会以为 我空手滚出去吧?
You didn't think I was rolling out of here naked, did you?
沃尔特 拜托 15英里 酷哥 来吧!
Walter, please!Fifteen, Dude!This is it!Let's take that hill!
沃尔特!
Walter!
在我们这里!
We have it!
在...我们这里!
好了 酷哥
Fuck it, Dude.
我们去打保龄吧
Let's go bowling.
酷哥 像我前妻那样说 这不是我能控制的
Aitz chaim he, Dude, as the ex used to say.
那是什么鬼意思?
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
我们该怎样和 李波斯基说呢?
What the fuck are we gonna tell Lebowski?
他...
Oh, him.
问题到底是什么?
I don't know. What exactly is the problem?
问题是...你...
The problem is...What do you mean, what's the...
我们根本没有...
There was no...We didn't...
他们一定会杀了 那可怜的女人
They're gonna kill that poor woman, man!
你在说什么?
What the fuck are you talking about?
那女人是个婊子绑架了自己
The poor woman, that poor slut kidnapped herself.
酷哥 你说过的
Come on, Dude. You said so yourself.
我说可能她绑架了自己
Man, I said I thought she kidnapped herself.
只有你才那么肯定
You're the one who's so fucking certain.
没错 酷哥100%肯定
That's right, Dude. 100% certain.
他们寄信要求下周比赛
They posted the next round for the tournament.
唐尼...我们的
Donny, shut the fuck...
对手是哪一队? 本周六 昆提那和...
When do we play? This Saturday. Quintana and...
周六? 那他们就要改期了
Saturday? Well, they'll have to reschedule.
沃尔特 我该怎么 和李波斯基说?
Walter, what am l gonna tell Lebowski?
我要和负责 安排赛事的混蛋说
I told that fuck down at the league office. Who's in charge of scheduling?
- 沃尔特 - 博克豪特
- Walter!- Burkhalter.
我跟他们说多少次了 我在安息日不打保龄
I told that kraut a fucking thousand times, I don't roll on shabbos!
他已经寄信了
Walter!They already posted it.
他可以撤回去!
Well, they can fucking un-post it!
谁会在乎?!他们一定会杀了那可怜的女人
Who gives a shit? They're gonna kill that poor woman, man!
我该怎么和李波斯基说? 酷哥
What am I gonna tell Lebowski? Come on, Dude.
很显然她已经 厌倦了这个游戏 已经想回家了
Eventually she'll get tired of her little game and, you know, wander on back.
你为什么不能在 周六打保龄 沃尔特?
How come you don't roll on Saturday, Walter?
我要过安息日
I'm shomer shabbos.
那是什么 沃尔特? 同时...
What's that, Walter? Yeah, and in the meantime,
我该怎么和李波斯基说?
what do I tell Lebowski?
周六就是安息日
Saturday, Donny, is shabbos, the Jewish day of rest.
那就意味者我不工作
That means I don't work, I don't drive a car,
不开车...
I don't fucking ride in a car,
不能数钱...
I don't handle money, I don't turn on the oven
而且肯定不能打保龄!
and I sure as shit don't fucking roll!
天啊
Sheesh.
安息日!
Shomer shabbos!
沃尔特...安息日
Walter, how am I gonna... Shomer shabbos!
够了!我要走了 酷哥
Oh, fuck!That's it. I'm out of here. Oh, come on, Dude.
酷哥!酷哥!
Dude!Dude!
你就告诉他...
You just tell him...
我们把钱扔下去了 一切就像...
Tell him we made the drop and everything went, you know...
怎么了?
Oh, yeah. How'd it go?
没什么 酷哥车上有些宝贝
Went all right. Dude's car got a little dinged up.
沃尔特 我们没去交换人质
Walter, we didn't make the fucking hand-off, man!
他们没拿到钱!
They didn't get the fucking money!
他们一定会...
And they're gonna... They're gonna...
他们一定会杀了 那可怜的女人
They're gonna kill that poor woman.
They're gonna kill that poor woman!
沃尔特 如果 你不能开车...
Walter, if you can't ride in a car,
你怎么去参加 安息日仪式?
then how do you get around on shabbos?
酷哥 你真的让我吃惊了
Really, Dude, you surprise me.
他们不会杀人的
They're not gonna kill shit.
他们一无是处
They're not gonna do shit.
- 他们能对她怎样? - 只是一帮乌合之众
- What can they do to her? - Bunch of fucking amateurs.
而且你看看
And meanwhile, look at the bottom line.
现在谁拿着那一百万呢?
Who's sitting on a million fucking dollars?
- 我说错了吗? - 沃尔特...
- Am I wrong? - Walter.
现在谁有一百万放在我们车子后面呢
Who's got a fucking million fucking dollars sitting in the trunk of our car?
我们的车 沃尔特? 他们呢? 只有我的脏内裤
Our car, Walter? And what do they got? My dirty undies.
那些白色内裤
My fucking whites!
酷哥
Say, Dude?
你的车呢?
Where is your car?
- 谁拿了你的内裤 沃尔特? - 你的车呢 酷哥?
- Who's got your undies, Walter? - Where's your car, Dude?
你不知道吗 沃尔特?
You don't know, Walter?
停在残疾人专用区的 可能被拖走了
It was parked in a handicap zone. Perhaps they towed it.
你都知道它被偷了
You fucking know it's been stolen.
肯定有这个可能 酷哥
Well, certainly that's a possibility, Dude.
该死的
Oh, fuck it.
- 你去哪里 酷哥? - 我要回家 唐尼
- Where you going, Dude? - I'm going home, Donny.
- 电话在响啊 酷哥 - 谢谢提醒 唐尼
- Phone's ringing, Dude. - Thank you, Donny!
是的...
Yeah.
绿色 有些棕色的 锈迹
Green with some brown, rust coloration.
在车里有什么 值钱的东西吗?
And was there anything of value in the car?
有的
Oh, yeah.
一台录音机 一些磁带 还有...
A tape deck, some Creedence tapes, and there was a...
我的公文包
My briefcase.
在公文包里面呢?
In the briefcase?
文件
Papers.
只是文件
Just papers.
我的文件 生意文件
You know, my papers, business papers.
你做什么生意 先生? 我现在失业
And what do you do, sir? I'm unemployed.
我的地毯也被偷了
My rug was also stolen.
你的地毯在车上吗?
Your rug was in the car?
不 在这里被偷的
No. Here.
可另外立案了?
Separate incidents.
酷哥不在家
The Dude is not in.
你们经常找回那些失车吗?
Do you find them much, these stolen cars?
有时吧
Sometimes.
但别对那录音机有太大希望
Wouldn't hold out much hope for the tape deck though.Or the Creedence.
那么...
What about the briefcase?
我的公文包呢? 李波斯基先生 我想见你
Mr. Lebowski, I'd like to see you.
请回电 我会派车接你
Call when you get home and I'll send a car for you.
我叫玛迪 李波斯基 我就是拿走你地毯的人
My name is Maude Lebowski. I'm the one who took your rug.
看来那案子已经解决了
Well, guess we can close the file on that one.
请稍等 李波斯基先生
I'll be with you in a moment, Mr. Lebowski.
女性的形态让你觉得 不舒服吗 李波斯基先生?
Does the female form make you uncomfortable, Mr. Lebowski?
- 这就是那样的一幅画吗? - 在某种意义上 是的
- Is that what this is a picture of? - In a sense, yes.
我的艺术被认为与女性的阴道有关
My art has been commended as being strongly vaginal,which bothers some men.
这个词让某些 男人觉得不自在
The word itself makes some men uncomfortable.
- 阴道 - 是吗?
- Vagina. - Oh, yeah?
是的 他们不喜欢听到
Yes, they don't like hearing it and find it difficult to say,
觉得难以启齿
whereas without batting an eye,
男人相对应的 就是他的阳具 或者叫...小弟弟
a man will refer to his dick, or his rod or his johnson.
小弟弟?
"Johnson"?
好了 李波斯基先生 我们说正事吧
All right, Mr. Lebowski, let's get down to cases.
我父亲告诉我 他同意了给你那张地毯
My father told me he agreed to let you have the rug,
但那曾经是我已故 母亲的一份礼物 所以他无权赠送给别人
but as it was a gift from me to my late mother, it was not his to give.
现在 你的脸上
Now, your face.
关于这次绑架...
As for this kidnapping.
没错 我知道此事 你的角色是送赎金的人
Yes, I know all about it, and I know that you acted as courier.
让我告诉你 这件事简直让人恶心
Let me tell you something. The whole thing stinks to high heaven.
没错 但让我解释 一下地毯的事情
Yeah, right, but let me explain something about the rug.
你喜欢性吗 李波斯基先生?
Do you like sex, Mr. Lebowski?
- 什么? - 性交 爱的身体行为
- Excuse me? - Sex, the physical act of love. Coitus.
你喜欢吗? 我刚在说我的地毯
Do you like it? I was talking about my rug.
你对性不感兴趣?
You're not interested in sex?
你说的是性交? 我也喜欢
You mean coitus? I like it, too.
这是关于男性对女权主义者的偏见认为我们讨厌性
It's a male myth about feminists that we hate sex.
这可以成为一种自然的 "性"致很高的产业
It can be a natural, zesty enterprise.
然而有某些人...
However, there are some people,
被称为色情狂
it is called satyriasis in men, nymphomania in women,
不能自控地参与而且 没有任何乐趣可言
who engage in it compulsively and without joy.
- 不是吧 - 是的 李波斯基先生
- Oh, no. - Oh, yes, Mr. Lebowski.
那些不幸的人不能去爱
These unfortunate souls cannot love, in the true sense of the word.
我们都认识的邦妮 就是其中之一
Our mutual acquaintance, Bunny, is one of these.
玛迪
Listen, Maude,
如果你的继母是个性爱狂 我很抱歉
I'm sorry if your stepmother is a nympho,
但我觉得这个与我的...
but, you know, I don't see what this has to do with...
你有卡鲁哇酒吗? 看看这个吧 先生
You have any Kahlua? Take a look at this, sir.
我认识这男人
Oh, I know that guy.
他是一个虚无主义者
He's a nihilist.
Karl Hungus啊
"Karl Hungus."
嗨
Hi. Hello.
总部说你这里的 线路有些问题
Mein dispatcher says there is something wrong with dein Kabel.
是的
Yeah. Come on in.
我不知道 出了什么问题
I'm not really sure exactly what's really wrong with the cable.
所以他们派我来 我是个专家
That's why they sent me. I am an expert.
电视机在这里
The TV's in here.
你一定能认出她
You recognize her, of course. Helga, bring my tools.
这是我的朋友莎莉
That's my friend Sherry.
她只是来洗澡的
She just came over to use the shower.
这故事非常无聊
The story is ludicrous.
我叫卡尔 维修工人
My name is Karl. Ich bin expert.
你一定是来修线路的
You must be here to fix the cable.
之后的事情 你也应该想象到了
Lord, you can imagine where it goes from here.
他修线路?
He fixes the cable?
别装傻 杰弗里
Don't be fatuous, Jeffrey.
这女人从事色情行业 对我来说是无关痛痒的
Little matter to me that this woman chose to pursue a career in pornography,
更不用说他勾搭上了 杰奇.特里赫姆
nor that she has been banging Jackie Treehorn,
以我们这年头的话来说
to use the parlance of our times.
然而我是李波斯基 基金会的两个托管人之一
However, I am one of the two trustees of the Lebowski Foundation,
另外一个是我父亲
the other being my father.
我们的基金会领养了 一些年轻人...
The foundation takes youngsters from Watts and...
是啊 那些成就者
Shit, yeah. The achievers.
没错 就是他们 我们对他们感到很骄傲
Little Lebowski Urban Achievers, yes, and proud we are of all of them.
我问父亲关于在基金户口的一百万提款的事情
I asked my father about his withdrawal of $1 million from the foundation account,
他就告诉了我这个绑架
and he told me about this abduction,
但我认为这是荒谬无耻的
but I tell you it is preposterous.
那个私通者想骗取 我父亲的钱财
This compulsive fornicator is taking my father for the proverbial ride.
是的 但我的...我正想说到你的地毯
Yeah, but my... I'm getting to your rug.
我和父亲相处并不融洽
My father and l don't get along.
他不赞同我的生活风格
He doesn't approve of my lifestyle and,
不必说 我也不赞同他的
needless to say, I don't approve of his.
但我不想就他的 行为诉诸法律
However, I hardly wish to make my father's embezzlement a police matter.
所以我建议 你向那些坏人...
So I'm proposing that you try to recover the money
要回那一笔钱
from the people you delivered it to.
我可以那样做的
Well, I could do that.
如果你成功做到了 我会将...
If you successfully do so,
收回数目的10% 作为你的赔偿
I will compensate you to the tune of 10% of the recovered sum.
十万...没错
A hundred... Thousand. Yes.
十万美金
Bones or clams or whatever you call them.
但是...我的...没错 还有你的地毯
Yeah, but what about my... Your rug, yes.
有了那笔钱你可以买到对我没有
Well, with that money you can buy any number of rugs
任何情感价值的地毯
that don't have sentimental value for me.
我还要对你下巴的 拳伤道歉
And I am sorry about that crack on the jaw.
那没什么...
Oh, that's fine. That doesn't even...
这是一位医生的名片他会为你服务的
Here's the name and number of a doctor who will look at it for you.
你不必付帐
You will receive no bill.
他是个彻头彻尾的好人
He's a good man and thorough.
你真体贴 不过...
That's thoughtful but...
请你去找他 他是个彻头彻尾的好人
Please see him, Jeffrey. He's a good man and thorough.
那么...好吧
Oh, well, all right.
他说 我老婆总是给我麻烦
So he says, "My wife's a pain in the ass.
让我不得安宁
"She's always busting my frigging agates.
我女儿嫁了一个无用的丈夫
"My daughter's married to a loser bastard.
我的屁股还长了皮疹 不能坐下来
"I got a rash so bad on my ass I can't even sit down.
但我不能抱怨什么
"But you know me, I can't complain."
没错
Oh, fucking A, man.
是啊
I got a rash, man. Fucking A.
我告诉你吧
I gotta tell you, Tone, man,
以前的我总是觉得很沮丧
earlier today I was really feeling shitty, man.
无精打采
Really down in the dumps.
失去了不少钱财...
Lost a little money...
别想那些了
Hey, you know what? Forget about it, huh? Forget about it.
算了吧
Yeah, fuck it, man.
没错 我不应该再担心那些事情 生活还要继续啊
You can't be worried about that shit. Life goes on, man.
到家了 先生
Well, home, sweet home, Mr. L.
看啊
Hey, yo. Come here.
你那位开大众汽车的 朋友是谁?
Who's your friend in the Volkswagen? Huh?
他跟随我们到这里的
Yeah. He followed us here.
他什么时候...啊!搞什么?
When did he start... Whoa!What the fuck?
进去里面 你这个混蛋
Get in the limo, you son of a bitch!No arguments!
小心点 我还拿着饮料
Hey!Hey!Careful, man!There's a beverage here!
开始说话 快点 你这个该死的混混
Start talking, and talk fast, you lousy bum.
我们在疯狂地找你 酷哥
We've been frantically trying to reach you, Dude.
我的钱在哪里?
Where is my goddamn money, you bum?
我们...我...
Well, we... I don't...
他们没收到 笨蛋!
They did not receive the money, you nitwit!
他们没收到那笔钱!
They did not receive the money!
她的性命在你手上!
Her life was in your hands!
这是我们所关注的 酷哥
This is our concern, Dude.
现在没什么搞砸了
No, man. Nothing is fucked here.
- 没什么搞砸了? - 是的
- Nothing is fucked? - No, man.
飞机已经撞毁了!
The goddamn plane has crashed into the mountain!
听我说 你要相信 那些人还是相信...
Man, come on. Who are you gonna believe, those guys or...
我们把钱扔下去了
We dropped off the damn money.
我们?
We?
我代表我们
I, the royal we.
像那些社论一样
You know. The editorial...
我按他们的 要求把钱扔下去
I dropped off the money exactly as per...
我得到的信息是很确切的
Look, man, I've got certain information. All right?
有些事情暴露了...
Certain things have come to light and...
你有没有想过...
You know, has it ever occurred to you
除了到处跑 还有责怪我...
that instead of, you know, running around, blaming me you know, given the nature of all this new shit,
这事情会比想象 之中更加...负责吗?
you know, this could be a lot more complex...
这也许不是预料中 那么简单的 你知道吗?
I mean, it's not just... It might not be just such a simple... You know?
你究竟在说些什么?
What in God's holy name are you blathering about?
我在告诉你我要说的
Well, I'll tell you what I'm blathering about.
我收到信息 伙计
I've got information, man.
有新的问题出现了
New shit has come to light.
而且是...
And, shit, man,
她绑架了她自己
she kidnapped herself.
是啊
Well, sure, man. Look at it. You know?
一个放荡女子...我们是这样说的...
A young trophy wife, in the parlance of our times, you know.
她在城里欠了很多债 还有那个色情电影制片人
She owes money all over town, including to known pornographers.
不过真的很酷
And that's cool. That's cool.
我要说的是她需要钱
I'm saying she needs money, man.
还有...他们肯定会说没拿到的
And, you know, of course they're gonna say they didn't get it
因为她想要更多
because she wants more, man.
她养了那么多白脸...
She's gotta feed the monkey. I mean...
不要说你从来没想过这些
Hasn't that ever occurred to you, man?
先生?
Sir?
没有 李波斯基先生 我从没想过
No, Mr. Lebowski, it had not occurred to me.
我们从没想过 酷哥
That had not occurred to us, Dude.
你知道...
Well, okay, you know?
新出现的麻烦和你们 并没有利害关系...
You guys aren't privy to all the new shit, so, you know...
但是...那是你们雇用我去做的
But, hey, that's what you... That's what you pay me for.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
你们现在能否...将我的两万元兑现呢?
do you think that you could give me my $20,000 in cash?
我本来要找我的 会计核对一下...
My concern is, and I've gotta check it with my accountant,
但这样我必须 交很多税 所以...
that this might bump me up into a higher tax...
布兰特...把信封给他
Brandt, give him the envelope.
如果你们给现金那就最好
Oh, well, if you've already got the check made out, that's cool.
我们早上收到这个
We received this this morning.
你的使命没有完成
Since you have failed to achieve,
那是如此简单的任务
even in the modest task which was your charge,
既然你偷了我的钱
since you have stolen my money,
既然你背叛了 我的信任...
since you have unrepentantly betrayed my trust,
我别无选择只能告诉你这个
I have no choice but to tell these bums
混混该做什么
to do whatever is necessary
你要赔偿那笔钱 李波斯基
to recover their money from you, Jeffrey Lebowski.
布兰特做我的证人我告诉你
And with Brandt as my witness, I will tell you this,
邦妮受到的伤害
any further harm visited upon Bunny
将10倍加于你头上
will be visited tenfold upon your head.
哦 天啦
By God, sir,
我不能再接受另一只脚趾
I will not abide another toe.I hear the cottonwoods whispering above
那不是她的脚趾 酷哥
That wasn't her toe, Dude.
那是谁的 沃尔特? 我怎么知道?
Whose toe was it, Walter? How the fuck should I know?
我知道的是没有 任何迹象表明...那指甲油 沃尔特
I do know that nothing about it indicates... The nail polish, Walter.
好了 酷哥
Fine, Dude.
那指甲油也可以 涂在其他人的脚趾上
As if it's impossible to get some nail polish, apply it to someone else's toe...
其他人的?
Someone else... Pinking shears.
他们怎么可以...
Where the fuck are they gonna get...
你要脚趾吗? 我可以找到
You want a toe? I can get you a toe.
相信我吧 肯定 有办法的 酷哥
Believe me, there are ways, Dude.
你不会想知道的 今天下午3点前
You don't wanna know about it, believe me. Yeah, but, Walter...
我就能给你一只脚趾 有指甲油的
Hell, I could get you a toe by 3:00 this afternoon with nail polish.
那些该死的混蛋 沃尔特...
These fucking amateurs. Walter...
他们给我送来了一只脚趾 我们本应该很害怕的
They send us a toe, we're supposed to shit ourselves with fear.
天呐 沃尔特...
Jesus Christ!Walter...
问题是...他们会杀了她的 沃尔特
The point is... They're gonna kill her, Walter,
然后他们就要来杀我
and then they're gonna kill me.
酷哥 那...
Dude, that's...
那只是威胁的手段
That's just the stress talking, man.
这让我觉得...是一些对他人无害的犯罪
Now, so far we have what appears to me to be a series of victimless crimes.
- 那脚趾呢?- 别说那脚趾了!
- What about the toe? - Forget about the fucking toe!
不好意思 你们可以小声一点吗?
Excuse me, sir. Could you please keep your voices down?
这是一间家庭餐厅
This is a family restaurant.
拜托了 告诉你 最高法院
Oh, please!Dear, for your information,
已经否决了这种限制!
the Supreme Court has roundly rejected prior restraint.
沃尔特 这和 第一修正案没关系
Come on. Walter, this is not a First Amendment thing, man.
如果你不冷静下来 我只能要求你离开
Sir, if you don't calm down, I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
我当年打越战出生入死
Lady, I got buddies who died face down in the muck
为了你们这些闲人在这里开家庭餐厅!
so that you and I can enjoy this family restaurant!
- 好了 我要走了 - 酷哥 别走啊
- All right, I'm out of here. - Hey, Dude, don't go away, man.
这事你我都有份 涉及到我们基本的自由!
Come on. This affects all of us, man!it's our basic freedoms!
我不走
I'm staying.
我喝完我的咖啡
I'm finishing my coffee.
享受着咖啡
Enjoying my coffee.
酷哥不在
The Dude is not in.
请留言 谢谢
ave a message after the beep. It takes a minute.
李波斯基先生 我是 洛杉矶警察局的罗探员
Mr. Lebowski, this is Duty O.e.Rolvaag of the LAPD.
我们找到了你的失车
We've recovered your automobile.
在北好莱坞停车场可以认领
It can be claimed at the North Hollywood Auto Circus there on Victory.
太好了
Their hours there are...
太好了!
Far out, man. Far fucking out!
这是私人住宅啊
Hey!This is a private residence, man.
漂亮的土拨鼠
Oh, nice marmot.
我们要那笔钱 李波斯基 我们要那笔钱 李波斯基
Where is the money, Lebowski? We wants the money, Lebowski!
你以为我们在开玩笑吗?
You think we are kidding or making with the funny stuff?
有些东西你还没梦想过 李波斯基
We could do things you haven't dreamed of, Lebowski.
我们什么也不相信 他什么也不相信 李波斯基
Ja, we believes in nothing. We believes in nothing, Lebowski. Nothing!
明天我们会回来将你的小弟弟切掉
And tomorrow we come back and we cut off yourjohnson.
- 什么? - 我说我们要将你的 小弟弟切掉!
- Excuse me? - I said, we cut off yourjohnson!
想想吧 李波斯基
Just think about that, Lebowski.
就是你那鸡巴 李波斯基
Your wiggly penis, Lebowski.
也许我们可以 扯下来 李波斯基
Ja. Maybe we stomp on it and squish it.
昨晚被人发现的停靠在桥墩底下
It was discovered last night in Van Nuys lodged against an abutment.
哪里?
Oh, man. Lodged where?
它没被撞散了架 已经算走运了 李波斯基先生
You're lucky she didn't get chopped, Mr. Lebowski.
他们一定在到处兜风
Oh, man!Must've been a joyride situation.
撞到挡土墙之后就遗弃了
They abandoned the vehicle once they hit the retaining wall.
我的公文包啊!不在里面!
Oh, my fucking briefcase, man!It's not here!Shit!
我在报告上看到了 很抱歉
Yeah, I saw that on the report. Sorry.
你得从另一边进去
You gotta get in on the other side.
后镜在路上找到的就在车子旁边
The side view was found on the road by the car.
那录音机还在 已经算你走运了 还有那唱片
You're lucky they left the tape deck though, and the Creedence.
天啊!什么气味?
Oh, Jesus!What's that smell, man?
也许有个混混在上面睡过
Yeah. It's probably a vagrant slept in the car.
或者被人当作厕所使用
Or maybe just used it as a toilet and moved on.
朋友...
Hey, man,
你一定能找到 那帮家伙
are you gonna find these guys?
或者...总有一些线索...
Or, you know, I mean... You got any promising leads or...
线索?
Leads?
当然有了
Yeah. Sure.
我会和罪案调查组的人说的
I'll just check with the boys down at the crime lab.
他们有4个人 可以调查这案子
They got four more detectives working on the case.
我们只是来换班的
They got us working in shifts!
线索!
Leads!
我唯一的愿望就是在那帮 德国佬切掉我小弟弟之前
My only hope is that the big Lebowski kills me
让那老李波斯基杀了我
before the Germans can cut my dick off.
线索!
Leads!
那太荒谬了 酷哥
Now, that is just ridiculous, Dude.
没人会切掉你的小弟弟
No one's going to cut your dick off.
谢谢你 沃尔特 我没说什么
Thank you, Walter. Not if I have anything to say about it.
谢谢 沃尔特
Thank you, Walter.
这让我觉得非常安全
That makes me feel very secure. Dude?
酷哥 让我内心非常温暖
That makes me feel very warm inside, man. Dude?
这件麻烦的事情
This whole fucking thing.
我可以和那带着 尿迹的地毯留在这里
I could be sitting here with just pee stains on my rug.
但我不会那样 该死的德国佬
But no, man, I got a, you know... Yeah. Fucking Germans.
什么也没改变
Nothing changes.
该死的纳粹 他们是纳粹吗 酷哥?
Fucking Nazis. They were Nazis, Dude?
唐尼 他们以阉割作为恐吓
Oh, come on, Donny. They were threatening castration!
我们要在 这里喋喋不休吗?
Uh-huh. Are we gonna split hairs here?
不 我错了吗?
No. Am I wrong?
他...他们是虚无主义者
Well, he didn't... Man, they were nihilists, man.
他们一直说自己 什么也不相信
They kept saying they believed in nothing.
虚无主义者
Nihilists.
该死的
Fuck me.
说说你对社会主义 有什么要求吧 酷哥
I mean, say what you want about the tenets of national socialism, Dude.
起码这是一种思潮
At least it's an ethos. Yeah.
我们不要忘记...不要忘记 酷哥...
And, also, let's not forget... Let's not forget, Dude,
收养野生动物 那两栖啮齿动物
that keeping wildlife, an amphibious rodent,
在这城市里面...
for, you know, domestic Within the city...
是违反法律的 你现在成了 动物管理员了吗?
That ain't legal, either. What are you, a fucking park ranger now?
不 我只是想...
No!I'm just trying to...
谁在乎那该死的土拨鼠呢?
Who gives a shit about the fucking marmot?
我们只是在表示同情 酷哥 该死的同情
We are sympathizing here, Dude. Fuck sympathy.
我不需要你们的同情 我要留着我的小弟弟
I don't need your fucking sympathy, man. I need my fucking johnson.
你要来做什么呢 酷哥? 你要振作起来!
What do you need that for, Dude? You have got to buck up, man!
你不能带着负面的 影响参加比赛
You cannot drag this negative energy into the tournament.
操那比赛 操你的 沃尔特
Fuck the tournament. Fuck you, Walter.
操那比赛?
Fuck the tournament?
酷哥 我明白你的心情
Okay, Dude. I can see you don't want to be cheered up here.
唐尼 我们去打一轮吧
Come on, Donny. Let's go get us a lane.
再来一杯 好的 酷哥
Another Caucasian, Gary. Right, Dude.
你看这都什么朋友 是啊 酷哥
Friends like these, huh, Gary? That's right, Dude.
See them tumbling down
Pledging their love to the ground
Lonely, but free, I'll be found
- 有好的撒尔沙酒吗? - 苏城的撒尔沙酒?
- You got a good sarsaparilla? - Sioux City Sarsaparilla?
是啊 那里的很好
Yeah. That's a good one.
你好吗 酷哥?
How're you doing there, Dude?
不是很好
Not too good, man.
- 很不顺心是吧? - 是啊
- One of those days, huh? - Yeah.
一个比我 贤明的人说过...
Well, a wiser fellow than myself once said,
有时候你吃掉熊...
"Sometimes you eat the bear and..."
非常感谢
Much obliged.
有时候...熊吃你
"Sometimes the bear, well, he eats you."
那是东方谚语吗?
That some kind of Eastern thing?
很遥远的
Far from it.
我喜欢你的风格 酷哥
I like your style, Dude.
我也在钻研你的风格
Oh, well, I dig your style, too, man.
你的风格很牛仔
Got a whole cowboy thing going.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有一件事 酷哥
There's just one thing, Dude.
什么?
What's that?
你说话有必要带那么多脏字吗?
Do you have to use so many cuss words?
你他妈的在说什么?
What the fuck are you talking about?
好吧 酷哥 坚持你的方式
Okay, Dude. Have it your way.
放轻松 酷哥
Take her easy, Dude.
谢谢
Yeah. Thanks, man.
你的电话 酷哥
Call for you, Dude.
- 喂?- 杰弗里 你还没去看医生
- Hello? - Jeffrey, you have not gone to the doctor.
是啊 我还没去
Oh, yeah, no. No, I haven't yet.
我想马上见你
I'd like to see you immediately.
- 你就是李波斯基 - 是啊
- So, you're Lebowski. - Yeah.
玛迪将你的事情都告诉我了
Maude has told me all about you.
她很快就回来 请坐
She'll be back in a minute. Sit down.
要喝点什么吗? 好的 白色俄罗斯
Do you want a drink? Yeah, sure. White Russian.
酒吧台在那边
The bar's over there.
- 你做什么的 李波斯基? - 你他妈的是什么人?
- So, what do you do, Lebowski? - Who the fuck are you, man?
玛迪的一个朋友 屁股裂开的朋友?
Just a friend of Maudie's. Yeah? The friend with the cleft asshole?
- 你做什么的? - 没什么
- What do you do? - Oh, nothing much.
- 你好 杰弗里 - 你好
- Hello, Jeffrey. - Hello.
你好吗? 玛迪
Yeah. How are you? Listen, Maude.
我必须...
I got to
向你请辞
tender my resignation or whatever
因为...你母亲似乎...真的被绑架了
because looks like your mother really was kidnapped after all.
几乎可以肯定她不是
She most certainly was not.
你为什么 有时候不肯听些客观的意见?
Hey, man, why don't you fucking listen occasionally?
你也许可以学到什么 现在...
You might learn something. Now, I got...
别称呼她为我母亲
Please don't call her my mother.
她是个罪犯而不是受害者
She's most definitely the perpetrator and not the victim.
我得到了 非常确切的证据...
I'm telling you, I've got pretty definitive evidence.
- 从谁那里得来? - 那个男人 奥利
- From who? - From the main guy, Uli.
奥利? 她在色情电影里面的搭档?
Uli Kunkel? Her costar in the beaver picture?
那电影...你认识那男人?
You mean vagina? I mean, you know the guy?
我已经介绍过他
I might have introduced them, for all I know.
你记得奥利吗?
Do you remember Uli?
他过去是个音乐家
He's a musician. Used to have a group, Autobahn.
看看我的收藏 70年代后期 发行过一张唱片
Look in my LP's. They released one album in the late '70s.
类似电子流行音乐
Their music is sort of a techno pop.
- 他在假扮诱骗者? - 是的
- So he's pretending to be the abductor? - Well, yeah.
杰弗里 你也不会 绑架一个熟悉的人
Look, Jeffrey, you don't really kidnap someone you're acquainted with.
绑架就不能让人质在 释放后指认自己
The whole idea is that the hostage can't identify you after you've let them go.
我知道
Well, I know that.
那家伙到底在抽哪根筋? 他是谁?
What the fuck is with this guy? Who is he?
诺克斯 哈灵顿 录像艺术师
Knox Harrington, the video artist.
那么钱在奥利那里?
So, Uli has the money.
其实不是
Well, no, not exactly.
这个非常复杂 玛迪
This is a very complicated case, Maude.
很多曲折
You know, a lot of ins, a lot of outs,
诸如此类的事物
a lot of what-have-yous
很多让我困惑的事情
and a lot of strands to keep in my head, man.
很多酷哥困惑的事情
You know, a lot of strands in the old Duder's head.
喂?
Hello?
如果钱不在奥利那里 那么会在谁手上?
If Uli doesn't have it, then who does?
是桑德拉
It's Sandra about the Biennale.
我必须接听这个你还有那医生的电话吗?
Look. I have to take this. Do you still have that doctor's number?
其实瘀伤也已经退了 杰弗里
No, really, it's not even bruised anymore. Oh, please, Jeffrey.
我不想对任何后遗症负责
I don't want to be responsible for any delayed aftereffects.
[意大利语]
后遗症?
Aftereffects?
[意大利语]
脱下你的短裤好吗 李波斯基先生?
Could you slide your shorts down, Mr. Lebowski, please?
不必了 她打在我这里
No, no, man. She hit me right here.
我知道 脱下短裤好吗?
I understand. Could you slide your shorts down, please?
Just got home from lllinois
Locked the front door, oh, boy
Got to sit down, take a rest on the porch
Imagination sets in
Pretty soon I'm singin'
Doo, doo, doo
Looking out my back door
Keeping mighty cool. There's a giant doing cartwheels
A statue wearing high heels
Look at all the happy creatures
Dancing on the lawn
A dinosaur Victrola listening to Buck Owens
Doo, doo, doo
Looking out my back door
Tambourines and elephants are playing in the band
Doo, doo, doo
Wondrous apparition provided by magician
Looking out my back door
Tambourines and elephants are playing in the band
Won't you take a ride on the flying spoon?
Doo, doo, doo
Bother me tomorrow
Today I'll buy no sorrows
Doo, doo, doo
Looking out my back door
他住在北好莱坞拉德弗德路 在那间IN&OUT汉堡包店附近
He lives in North Hollywood on Radford, near the In-N-Out Burger.
在那间IN&OUT汉堡包店附近
No, the In-N-Out Burger's on Camrose.
那里的汉堡包 很好吃啊 沃尔特
Near the In-N-Out Burger. Those are good burgers, Walter.
闭嘴 唐尼 那小孩在读九年级 酷哥
Shut the fuck up, Donny. The kid is in the ninth grade, Dude.
他父亲是...
And his father is... Are you ready for this?
一个叫迪比.塞勒斯的作家
His father is Arthur Digby Sellers.
那是什么人?
Who the fuck is that?
迪比.塞勒斯?
Who the fuck is Arthur Digby Sellers? Who the...
听说过一个叫"烙印"的 节目吗 酷哥?
Have you ever heard of a little show called Branded, Dude?
我知道...
Yes, yes, I...
只有一个人 可以生存的那个?
"All but one man died there at Bitter Creek."
我知道 沃尔特  那又怎样了?
I know the fucking show, Walter. So what?
那个该死的迪比.塞勒斯 写了156章 酷哥
Fucking Arthur Digby Sellers wrote 156 episodes, Dude.
连续剧啊
The bulk of the series.
- 不是个容易对付的家伙 - 是啊
- Not exactly a lightweight. - No.
而他的儿子是个笨笨
And yet his son is a fucking dunce.
我们要到他家里
Anyway, we'll go there after the what-have-you.
那孩子应该很容易对付的
We'll brace the kid. Should be a pushover.
我们要到 IN&OUT汉堡包店附近啊
We'll be near the ln-N-Out Burger.
闭嘴 唐尼!
Shut the fuck up, Donny!
我们要对那孩子逼供 应该很容易对付
We'll go out there, we'll brace the kid. He should be a pushover.
我们要夺回 那该死的一百万
We'll get that fucking million dollars back,
如果他还没花光的话
if he hasn't spent it already.
整整一百万啊
A million fucking clams.
是啊 我们就要到...IN&OUT汉堡包店
And, yes, we'll be near the... In-N-Out.
吃些汉堡包 喝几杯啤酒 说几个笑话
Shh!Shh!Some burgers, some beers. A few laughs.
我们的麻烦就要结束了 酷哥
Our fucking troubles are over, Dude.
该死的!
Oh, fuck me, man.
那孩子已经 把钱花光了!
That kid's already spent all the money, man.
就那辆新车? 还远着呢 酷哥
New Vette? Hardly, Dude.
起码还剩下90多万 看他买了什么配件
I'd say he still has $060,000, $070,000 left, depending on the options.
在车里等着 唐尼
Wait in the car, Donny.
谁? 皮拉尔是吗?
Yes? Pilar?
我是沃尔特 这是我的助手杰弗里
My name is Walter Sobchak. This is my associate, Jeffrey Lebowski.
我们是来找拉里的
We came to talk about little Larry.
- 可以进来吗? - 可以
- May we come in? - Yes, yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
就是他 酷哥
That's him, Dude.
你好 先生!
And a good day to you, sir!
请坐
Sit down, please.
拉里 那位先生来了!
Larry, sweetie, the man is here!
他...他还在写作吗?
Is he... Does he still write?
不 他有健康问题
Oh, no, no. He has health problems.
我想说的是...
Sir, I just want to say
我们...个人来说都是你的...
that we're both, on a personal level,
庞大的粉丝团里的人之一
really enormous fans.
"烙印" 尤其是前面的章节
Branded, especially the early episodes,
对我们很有启发
was truly a source of inspiration.
亲爱的 下来啊!这男人是个警察
Sweetie, sit down. This man is the police.
不 我们不想给人警察的印象
Oh, no, ma'am. We didn't want to give the impression that we were police, exactly.
我们不希望报警
We're hoping it won't be necessary to call the police.
但这取决于小拉里
But that's up to little Larry here.
对吗 拉里?
Isn't it, Larry?
这是你的作业吗 拉里?
Is this your homework, Larry?
Is this your homework, Larry? Look, man, it...
酷哥 这是你的作业吗 拉里?
Dude. Please? Is this your homework, Larry?
问他关于车子的事情
Just ask him about the car, man.
这是你的吗? 这是你的作业吗 拉里?
Is this yours, Larry? Is this your homework, Larry?
外面的车是你的吗?
Is that your car out front?
这是你的作业吗 拉里? 我们知道这是他的作业!
Is this your homework, Larry? We know it's his fucking homework!
钱在哪里 你这个臭小子?
Where's the fucking money, you little brat?
拉里...你听说过越战的事情吗?
Look, Larry, have you ever heard of Vietnam?
你真让人头痛 我们知道这是你的作业
For Christ's sake, Walter. You are entering a world of pain, son.
你偷了我们的车
We know that this is your homework. We know that you stole the car.
还有那些钱!还有那些钱!
And the fucking money. And the fucking money!
我们知道这是你的作业
And we know that this is your homework!
我们要切掉你的小弟弟 拉里
We're gonna cut your dick off, Larry.
你快要了你爸爸的命了
You're killing your father, Larry.
好了 这是没意义的
All right. This is pointless.
该用B计划了
Okay, time for Plan B.
你也许想看看外面 拉里
You might want to watch out that front window, Larry.
这就是惹怒陌生人的后果!
Son, this is what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass!
用语言讲不通是吧
A little language problem here.
那臭小子惹我发火
Little prick's stonewalling me.
沃尔特!
Walter.
你在干什么?
What are you doing, man?
What are you doing?
看吧 拉里
Here you go, Larry.
看到了吗?
You see what happens?
看到了吗? 拉里
You see what happens, Larry?
看到了吗?
You see what happens? Oh, great.
这就是惹怒陌生人的后果!
This is what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass, Larry.
看到吗? 拉里
This is what happens, Larry.
看到了吗? 拉里
You see what happens, Larry?
这就是惹怒陌生人的后果!
You see what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass?
看到吗
This is what happens!
看到吗 拉里?
You see what happens, Larry?
这就是惹怒陌生人的后果!
Do you see what happens, Larry, when you fuck a stranger in the ass?
这就是后果!
This is what happens, Larry!
不!这就是后果!
My car!My baby!This is what happens, Larry!
这就是后果!
This is what happens when you fuck a stranger...
你在干什么? 住手!
What the fuck are you doing, man? Stop it!
我上周才买到这辆车的!
Hey, man. I just bought that fucking car last week!
对不起 我要杀了你!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!I'm sorry!I'm gonna fucking kill you!
我上周才买到这辆车的!
I just bought the fucking car last week!Come on, man.
我要砸了你的车!
I'll kill your fucking car, man!
那不是他的车啊!
No, no. Hey, hey, that's not his!Hey!
该死的!不!
God damn it!Whoa!Oh, no!
去你的!
Fuck you!Man. No.
你喜欢吗? 去你的!
You like that? Fuck you!
- 我要砸了你的车!- 不 不 不
- I'll kill your fucking car!- No. No, no. No.
我要砸了你的车!
I'll kill your fucking car!
我接受你的道歉
I accept your apology.
不 我只是...想从现在开始自己处理
No, I just want to handle it by myself from now on.
不 不 不!
No. No. No!
那与此事无关
That has nothing to do with it.
是的 车子熬到回家 你在家里打电话给我
Yes, the car made it home. You're calling me at home.
不 沃尔特 看起来不是的...拉里不会说出什么
No, Walter, it did not look like Larry was about to crack!
那是你的猜测
Well, that's your perception.
沃尔特 你说得对
You know, Walter, you're right.
有一句话我还没说
There is an unspoken message here.
就是"去你的"!别管我了!
It's, "Fuck you!Leave me the fuck alone!"
没错 我会去练习的
Yeah, I'll be at practice.
戴上你的尿布 李波斯基
Pin your diapers on, Lebowski.
杰奇.特里赫姆想见你
Jackie Treehorn wants to see you.
杰奇.特里赫姆知道 你是哪个李波斯基
Jackie Treehorn knows which Lebowski you are, Lebowski.
杰奇.特里赫姆想见 那个游手好闲的李波斯基
Jackie Treehorn wants to see the deadbeat Lebowski.
你要应付的不是白痴
You're not dealing with morons here.
你好 酷哥 谢谢你的到来
Hello, Dude. Thanks for coming.
我是杰奇 特里赫姆
I'm Jackie Treehorn.
你这里地方不错啊
This is quite a pad you got here, man.
像世外桃源
Completely unspoiled.
喝点什么吗 酷哥? 白色俄罗斯 谢谢
What's your drink, Dude? A White Russian. Thanks.
白色俄罗斯
White Russian.
你的色情电影生意怎样了? 我也不知道 酷哥
How's the smut business, Jackie? I wouldn't know, Dude.
我是做出版的 娱乐 政治主张
I deal in publishing, entertainment, political advocacy.
一种僵局? 很遗憾 那是对的
Which one's Logjammin'? Yes, regrettably, it's true.
成人娱乐被加上了标准
Standards have fallen in adult entertainment.
这是录像 酷哥
It's video, Dude.
既然我们要和那些 业余的家伙竞争
Now that we're competing with those amateurs,
我们可以投资一些 有情节的故事 加大生产量
we can't afford to invest in little extras like story,
加入感情
production value, feelings.
人们忘记了...大脑是最大的情欲地带
You know, people forget that the brain is the biggest erogenous zone.
也许在你身上是的
On you maybe.
当然有利也有弊
Of course, you have to take the good with the bad.
可以用新的技术 做一些刺激的事情
New technology permits us to do very exciting things
那些交互式的色情软件
in interactive erotic software.
未来的冲击波 酷哥 100%电子化
Wave of the future, Dude. 100% electronic.
我还是用手好了
Well, I still jerk off manually.
当然了 我知道你很迫不及待
Of course you do. I can see you're anxious for me to get to the point.
我们开门见山 酷哥
Well, here it is, Dude.
邦妮在哪里?
Where's Bunny?
- 我还以为你知道呢 - 我怎么会知道?
- Well, I thought you might know that, man. - Why would l?
她为了那一笔数目不小的 债而从我这里逃跑了
She only ran off to get away from that rather sizable debt to me.
不 她没逃跑 只是...
No, she didn't run off. She's been...
那绑架的故事 我听说了 省下吧
I heard that kidnapping story, so save it.
我知道你被夹在中间 酷哥
I know you're mixed up in all this, Dude.
我也不在乎你想从 他丈夫那里得到什么好处
And I don't care what you're trying to get from the husband.
那是你的事情
That's your business.
我要说的是我要我的东西
All I'm saying is I want mine.
是啊
Yeah, right, man.
有很多方面
I mean, there are a lot of facets to this,
很多部分...
a lot of interested parties.
不好意思
Excuse me.
嗯?
Yeah?
是啊
Oh, yeah?
那是什么?
Where is that?
好了
All right. Yeah.
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 原谅我 - 没问题
- Forgive me. - No problemo, man.
如果我找到你的钱...
So, if I can find your money,
对我有什么好处?
what's in it for the Dude?
那当然是可以商量的 再来一杯吗?
Well, of course, there's that to discuss. You want a refill?
当然好了 10%的费用
Yeah, does the pope shit in the woods? 10% finder's fee.
- 好吗? - 好的 成交
- That all right? - Okay. Done, Jackie.
好 我欣赏你做生意的方式
I dig the way you do business, man.
你的钱在一个叫 拉里.塞勒斯的小孩那里
Your money is being held by a kid named Larry Sellers.
他住在北好莱坞拉德弗德路...
He lives in North Hollywood on Radford,
在IN&OUT汉堡包附近
by the ln-N-Out Burger.
他是个臭小子
Fucking brat.
但我想你的手下...一定能搞定的 他才15岁
But I'm sure your goons can get it off him. I mean, he's 15.
该死的学生
Flunking social studies.
如果你可以...
So, if you could just
写一张支票 50万的10%...
write me a check for my 10% of half a million,
5万...我马上就告辞
5 grand, I'll go out and mingle.
你的酒调得不赖啊 杰奇
You mix a hell of a Caucasian, Jackie.
一个15岁的小子
Fifteen-year-old kid.
那是开玩笑吗? 不
Is this some sort of a joke? No. No joke.
不是开玩笑的 就在那小子那里
No funny stuff, Jackie. The kid's got it.
嗨
Hi, fellas.
那小子想要一辆车
Kid just wanted a car.
酷哥只想要回他的地毯
All the Dude ever wanted was his rug back.
我并不贪心
Not greedy.
它真的...
It really
跟我屋很搭调
tied the room together.
酷哥接受了黑暗的洗礼
Darkness washed over the Dude.
就像在没有月亮的 晚上在海上航行
Darker than a black steer's tokus on a moonless prairie night.
进入一个无底洞
There was no bottom.
杰奇 特里赫姆出品
主演:酷哥
玛迪 李波斯基
保龄情史
Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah
What condition my condition was in
I woke up this morning with the sundown shining in
I found my mind in a brown paper bag within
I tripped on a cloud and fell-a eight miles high
I tore my mind on a jagged sky
I just dropped in
To see what condition my condition was in
Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah
What condition my condition was in
I pushed my soul in a deep, dark hole
And then I followed it in
I watched myself crawlin' out
As I was a-crawlin' in
I got up so tight
I couldn't unwind
I saw so much I broke my mind
I just dropped in
To see what condition my condition was in
Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah
What condition my condition was in
Someone painted "April Fool"
In big, black letters on a "Dead End" sign
I had my foot on the gas as I left the road
And blew out my mind
Eight miles out of Memphis and I got no spare
Eight miles straight up downtown somewhere
I just dropped in
To see what condition my condition was in
I said I just dropped in
Yeah, yeah
O? yeah
He was innocent
Not a charge was true
And they say he ran away branded
这是你唯一的身份证明?
Is this your only ID?
我知道我的权力
I know my rights, man.
你什么也不知道 李波斯基
You don't know shit, Lebowski.
我要一个律师
I want a fucking lawyer, man.
我要...比尔 克斯勒
I want Bill Kunstler, man,
或者朗恩 库奇
or Ron Kuby.
特里赫姆先生告诉我们...
Mr. Treehorn tells us that he had to eject you
他将你从派对里赶出去
from his garden party,
你喝醉了 并失去控制
that you were drunk and abusive.
特里赫姆先生把什么事都看做女人
Mr. Treehorn treats objects like women, man.
特里赫姆先生 对这城市的贡献很大
Mr. Treehorn draws a lot of water in this town.
但你什么贡献也没有 李波斯基
You don't draw shit, Lebowski.
这是个 宁静的海滩社区
Now, we got a nice quiet little beach community here,
而我要保证它的宁静
and I aim to keep it nice and quiet.
我说明白一点
So let me make something plain.
我不喜欢你在这里搞事 骚扰这里的市民 李波斯基
I don't like you sucking around bothering our citizens, Lebowski.
我不喜欢你的鸟名字
I don't like your jerk-off name.
不喜欢你的鸟脸
I don't like your jerk-off face.
不喜欢你的鸟行为
I don't like your jerk-off behavior.
我不喜欢你...怪胎
And I don't like you, jerk-off.
听明白了吗?
Do I make myself clear?
对不起 我刚才没在听
I'm sorry. I wasn't listening.
该死的法西斯!
Fucking fascist!
远离马里布 李波斯基!
Stay out of Malibu, Lebowski.
远离马里布 混蛋!
Stay out of Malibu, deadbeat!
将你的屁股从 我的社区带走
Keep your ugly, fucking, gold-bricking ass out of my beach community.
I want to sleep with you
In the desert tonight
With a billion stars all around
天啊...换个频道好吗?
Jesus, man. Could you change the channel?
去你妈的!如果你 不喜欢我的音乐
Fuck you, man!If you don't like my fucking music,
就别坐我的车!
get your own fucking cab!
我真的...
I had a really rough...
我要将你踢出去
I'll pull off to the side and kick your ass out.
我今晚真的很倒霉啊 我讨厌老鹰乐队
Man, come on. I had a rough night, and I hate the fucking Eagles, man.
滚出去!出去!
Out of my fucking cab!Out!Man!
嗨!嗨!
Man!Man!Hey!
There's a thousand pretty women waiting out there
And they're all livin' devil may care
And I'm just the devil with love to spare
So viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas
天啊!
Oh, Jesus!
杰弗里
Jeffrey.
玛迪? 爱我吧
Maude? Love me.
那是我的浴袍啊
That's my robe.
告诉我你的过去吧 杰弗里
Tell me about yourself, Jeffrey.
其实没太多好说的
Well, not much to tell.
我曾经是休伦湖港口 声明的创作者之一
I was one of the authors of the Port Huron Statement.
休伦湖港口声明的原本
The original Port Huron Statement. Uh-huh.
不是那经过 妥协的第二版本
Not the compromised second draft.
然后...
Then I...
你听说过西雅图七侠团体吗?
You ever hear of the Seattle Seven?
那就是我
That was me.
还有另外6个人...
And there were six other guys.
后来做了一段时间音乐经理人
And then the music business, briefly.
- 是吗? - 是啊
- Oh? - Yeah.
Metallica的经理人
Roadie for Metallica.
"Speed of Sound"巡演
Speed of Sound tour.
一帮傻瓜
Bunch of assholes.
然后 做些这个 做些那个
And then, you know, little of this, little of that.
我的事业最近停滞了
My career's slowed down a little lately.
你有什么消遣?
What do you do for recreation?
通常是打保龄
Well, the usual.
和开车兜风
Bowl, drive around,
偶然吃点迷幻药
the occasional acid flashback.
你的屋子怎么了?
What happened to your house?
杰奇 特里赫姆 将这里翻了一遍
Oh, Jackie Treehorn trashed the place.
他以为我有你父亲的钱
He thought I had your father's money.
他在我不在 这里的时候干的
He got me out of the way while he looked for it.
- 要鸡尾酒吗? - 不了 谢谢
- Cocktail? - No, thanks.
那不是我父亲的钱 是基金会的
It's not my father's money. It's the foundation's.
为什么他觉得你有呢? 谁知道呢?
Why did he think you have it? Who does?
那个中学生拉里 真是个该死的臭小子
Oh, Larry Sellers, this high school kid. Real fucking brat.
这是一个非常 复杂的案子 玛迪
You know, this is a very complicated case, Maude.
很多曲折
A lot of ins, a lot of outs.
不幸的是 我得坚持一个 很严格的...
You know, fortunately, I'm adhering to a pretty strict, drug regimen
用药规则 不让自己放纵 你知道的
to keep my mind, you know, limber,
已经非常接近 你父亲的钱了
and I'm very fucking close to your father's money.
我一直在说那是 基金会的钱
I keep telling you, it's the foundation's money.
我父亲没钱的
Father doesn't have any.
你说什么? 他很富有啊
What are you talking about? He's fucking loaded.
不 那些是我母亲的遗产
No, no. The wealth is all Mother's.
不 他是管理者...
No, he runs stuff.
我们的确让他管理 其中一间公司
We did let him run one of the companies briefly,
但他做得很不好 不 你知道的
but he didn't do very well at it. Oh, he's, you know...
他现在帮助管理 一个慈善机构
No, he helps administer the charities now,
而我给他相应的养老金
and I give him a reasonable allowance.
他自己没钱的
He has no money of his own.
我知道他介绍自己的方式
I know how he likes to present himself.
他的缺点就是虚荣 于是 那个婊子...
Father's weakness is vanity, hence the slut.
你认为他...
Do you think he...
怎么了? 你在做瑜珈
What is that, yoga?
这样可以增加怀孕的机会
It increases the chances of conception.
- 增加...? - 是啊
- Increases... Well, yes.
你以为那是为什么? 玩游戏吗?
What did you think this was all about? Fun and games?
我要生孩子
I want a child.
让我...
Okay, yeah, okay.
让我解释一下我自己
But let me... Let me explain something about the Dude.
杰弗里 我不需要一个搭档
Look, Jeffrey, I don't want a partner.
事实上我不想要一个孩子的父亲
In fact, I don't want the father to be someone I have to see socially
不管是名义上的还是我要自己养育我的孩子
or who will have any interest in raising the child himself.
所以那个医生...没错
Oh. So, that doctor... Exactly.
你的脸怎么了?
Now, what happened to your face?
杰奇 特里赫姆 也那样打你吗?
Did Jackie Treehorn do that as well?
不 是那个该死的 马里布警察 一个反动分子
No, it was the chief of police of Malibu, a real reactionary.
你的父亲...
So, your father...
我明白了 什么?
Oh, yeah, I get it. Yeah. Yeah. What?
我对这案子的想法...已经很清楚了
Oh, man. My thinking about this case has become very uptight.
嗯
Yeah.
你父亲
Your father.
杰弗里 你在说什么?
Jeffrey, what are you talking about?
杰弗里!
Jeffrey!
沃尔特 如果你在...
Walter, if you're there, pick up the fucking phone, man.
快拿起电话
Come on, Walter.
这是急事 酷哥?
Pick it up, man. This is an emergency. Dude? Dude?
沃尔特 我在家 我要你马上开车来接我
Yeah. Listen, Walter. I'm at my place. I need you to come pick me up.
- 我不能开车 酷哥 今天是安息日 - 什么?
- I can't drive, Dude. It's Erev shabbos. - What?
- 安息日 - 什么?
- Erev shabbos. - What?
安息日 我不能开车!
Erev shabbos. I can't drive. Man!
本来听电话也不行的 除非是急事
I'm not even supposed to pick up the phone unless it's an emergency.
- 这就是急事啊 - 我知道
- This is a fucking emergency!- I understand.
所以我听了电话
That's why I picked up the phone.
沃尔特 你这个混蛋 我们得去帕萨迪纳
Walter, you fuck. We gotta go to Pasadena, man.
快来接我 不然我退出 那该死的保龄球赛
Come pick me up or I'm off the fucking bowling team.
快出来
Get out of that fucking car, man!
出来!
Get out of that fucking car!
出来
Get the fuck out of the car, man.
出来...
Get out of the fucking...
你到底是谁? 别紧张
Who the fuck are you, man? Easy, man!
别紧张
Relax, man.
我无意伤害你
No physical harm intended.
你到底是谁? 为什么跟踪我?
Who the fuck are you? Why you following me around?
说啊 混蛋 我是希姆斯兄弟的人
Come on, fuckhead!Relax, man. I'm a brother shamus.
希姆斯兄弟?
Brother Shamus?
像那些爱尔兰僧人?
Like an Irish monk?
你在说什么鬼话?
What the fuck are you talking about?
我叫达菲诺 像你一样是个私家侦探
My name is Da Fino. I'm a private snoop, like you, man.
- 什么? - 侦探
- What? - A dick, man.
我很欣赏你的工作
And let me tell you something, I dig your work.
两头都应付得了
Playing one side against the other, in bed with everybody.
还能和美人消魂 我不是...
Fabulous stuff, man. I'm not...
别靠近我的女性朋友
Fuck it, man. Just stay away from my fucking lady friend.
我不是来找你的 特别女朋友麻烦
Hey, I'm not messing with your special lady.
她不是我的特别女朋友 她是个大麻烦
She's not my special lady. She's my fucking lady friend.
我只是帮助她怀孕 我不是...
I'm just helping her conceive, man!Hey, man. I'm not...
你为谁工作? 李波斯基?
Who are you working for? Lebowski?
杰奇.特里赫姆?
Jackie Treehorn?
克纳森
The Kneutsons.
克纳森是什么鬼东西?
Who the fuck are the Kneutsons?
克纳森家要 寻找他们的女儿
The Kneutsons, it's a wandering daughterjob.
邦妮.李波斯基
Bunny Lebowski, man.
她的真名叫弗恩.克纳森
Her real name is Fawn Kneutson.
她父母想找她
Her parents want her back, see?
天啊
Jesus fucking Christ.
她一年前离家出走了
Crazy, huh? Ran away about a year ago.
克纳森家说找到她时 要给她看这些
The Kneutsons told me I should show her this when I found her.
家族的农场 在明尼苏达州的
It's the family farm. It's outside Moorhead, Minnesota.
他们觉得这个会让她思乡
They think it'll make her homesick. Oh, boy.
他们怎么还能保留那农场?
How are you gonna keep them down on the farm once they've seen Karl Hungus?
她被绑架了
She's been kidnapped, Da Fino. Oh, man.
也许不是的
Or I don't know. Maybe not.
但是她肯定不在附近
But she's definitely not around.
也许我们可以交换信息
Hey, maybe you and me could pool our resources,
职业道德啊
trade information.Professional courtesy?
明白我的意思吗?
Compeers. You know what I mean?
明白 你消失吧
Yeah, yeah, I get it. Fuck off, Da Fino.
不要靠近我的...
And stay away from my special...
麻烦的女性朋友
From my fucking lady friend, man!
我要橘子薄饼
The lingonberry pancake.
[德语]
橘子薄饼
Lingonberry pancakes.
Three pigs in blanket.
[德语]
她要橘子薄饼
She has lingonberry pancakes.
[德语]
我们都搞砸了 什么报酬都没得到
I mean, we totally fucked it up, man. We fucked up his payoff.
那些绑架的人都被惹怒了
We got the kidnappers all pissed off.
李波斯基经常对我大喊
And Lebowski, you know, he yelled at me a lot,
但他什么也没做
but he didn't do anything, huh?
有时候...
Well, sometimes it's a cathartic... No, no.
我是说 既然他知道 我什么也做不了
I'm saying that if he knows I'm a fuckup,
为什么要我去找她老婆回来?
why does he leave me in charge of getting his wife back?
因为他不想她回来
Because he doesn't fucking want her back, man.
他已经对她没兴趣了 那些都是演戏的
He's had enough. He no longer digs her. It's all a show.
但为什么他要拿出 一百万呢?
Okay, but then why doesn't he give a shit about his million bucks?
他知道我们不会把 那一百万交给绑匪
I mean, he knows we never handed off his briefcase,
但他从没要求拿回来
but he never asked for it back.
那箱子里面根本 没有一百万
The million bucks was never in the briefcase.
那箱子是空的
The briefcase was fucking empty, man.
那混蛋想他们杀了她
The asshole was hoping that they would kill her.
你扔出去的是一个诱饵
You threw out a ringer for a ringer.
但为什么要那么急呢?
Okay, but how does all this add up to an emergency?
我知道你在说什么 酷哥 他留着那笔钱
I'm saying, I see what you're getting at, Dude. He kept the money.
我要说的是...
My point is...
今天是安息日
Here we are, it's shabbos, the Sabbath,
只是关乎人命的 事情才能去做
which I'm allowed to break only if it's a matter of life or death.
别吹牛了好吗 沃尔特? 你根本不是犹太人
Will you come off it, Walter? You're not even fucking Jewish, man.
你在说什么?
What the fuck are you talking about?
你是个波兰天主教徒
Man, you're fucking Polish Catholic!
你在说什么?
What the fuck are you talking about?
我和辛迪雅结婚后就改宗了 酷哥
I converted when I married Cynthia. Come on, Dude.
嗯 嗯...你知道的
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. You know this.
5年前你们就离婚了
And five fucking years ago, you were divorced.
那你觉得应该怎样? 你离婚之后
So what are you saying? When you get divorced,
你就可改变信仰了? 不做犹太人了?
you turn in your library card? You get a new license?
这是公路吗?
You stop being Jewish? This is the driveway.
我是一个犹太人
Jewish as fucking Tevye. Man.
这都是因为辛迪雅 而产生的病态
You know, it's all a part of your sick Cynthia thing.
照顾她留下的小狗...去那些犹太人集会...
Man, taking care of her fucking dog, going to her fucking synagogue.
你还活在你的过去
You're living in the fucking past.
那是有3000年 历史的传统
Three thousand years of beautiful tradition, from Moses to Sandy Koufax.
你说得对我还活在过去!
You're goddamn right I'm living in the fucking past!
天啊
I've... Jesus.
怎么了?
What the hell happened?
So viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas
我们走 妈的
Let's go. Fuck it.
她在哪里?
Where was she, man?
去了探访朋友
Visiting friends of hers in Palm Springs.
她刚离开的没告诉我们
She just picked up and left, never bothered to tell us.
我想那该死的虚无 主义者知道她在哪里
Well, I guess the fucking nihilists knew where she was.
酷哥 她没绑架自己
Jesus, Dude. She never even kidnapped herself.
这位是谁 酷哥? 我是个退伍军人
Who is this gentleman, Dude? Who am l? I'm a fucking veteran.
我是个退伍军人
Come on!That's who I am.
他不应该来这里的 酷哥 李先生现在非常生气
You shouldn't go in there, Dude. He's very angry.
你好
So, man.
她回来了 但不是因为你们
So? She's back, no thanks to you.
钱在哪里 李波斯基?
Where's the fucking money, Lebowski?
从那基金会提出来的一百万!
A million bucks from fucking, needy, little Urban Achievers!
你是个人渣!
You are scum, man!
他到底是谁? 我是谁?
Who the hell is he? Who am I? Who am I?
我是一个非常讨厌
Walter. I'm the guy that's gonna kick your phony,
你那些诡计的人
gold-bricking ass, that's who I am. Man.
他知道那箱子是空的
We know the briefcase was fucking empty.
我们知道你自己 留下了那一百万
We know you kept the million bucks for yourself.
你们有你的故事 我有我的故事
You have your story, I have mine.
我说我把钱委托给你们了 而你们偷走了
I say I entrusted the money to you and you stole it.
如果我们想过的话 你那些该死的钱!
As if we would ever dream of taking your bullshit money!
你以为邦妮被绑架了
You thought that Bunny had been kidnapped,
而你很高兴
and you were fucking glad, man.
可以用作让钱消失的借口
You could use it as an excuse to make some money disappear.
你需要的只是 一个傻子做你的替罪羊
All you needed was a sap to pin it on. You just met me.
你这个人渣!
You... You human paraquat.
这里有一个失败者
You figured, "Oh, here's a loser, you know, a deadbeat.
一个没人理会的家伙
"Somebody this square community won't give a shit about."
你不是吗?
Well, aren't you?
我是 不过...你们都出去
Well, yeah, but... Get out, both of you.
看那该死的混蛋 酷哥 还假扮成百万富翁
Look at that fucking phony, Dude, pretending to be a fucking millionaire.
你们这些混混 给我滚出去!
Out of this house now, you bums!
让我告诉你别的事情
Let me tell you something else.
我见过很多脊椎炎的 例子 酷哥 这家伙是假冒的
I've seen a lot of spinals, Dude, and this guy's a fake.
该死的骗子 别靠近我!
A fucking gold-bricker. Stay away from me, mister!
他可以走路的
This guy fucking walks.
没什么比这个更加肯定了
I've never been more certain of anything in my life.
走开!
You stay away from me!
沃尔特 他是个残废
Walter, for Christ's sake, man!He's a cripple.
快啊
I said!Get away from me!Come on. Come on.
走开!放他下来吧!
Walter, put him down, man!
我会的 酷哥!来吧!
Yeah, I'll put him down, Dude. Walk!Achtung, baby!
帮我把他放回椅子上面去
Come on, man. Help me put him back in his chair.
当然你会看到一些坦克战的
Sure you'll see some tank battles,
但在沙漠作战和 在丛林作战非常不一样
but fighting in desert is very different from fighting in canopy jungle.
越战是步兵的战斗 所以这个对我...
I mean, Nam was a foot soldier's war, whereas this thing should...
小菜一碟
You know, should be a piece of cake.
我有一支M16 而不是一辆坦克
I mean, I had an M16, Jacko, not an Abrams fucking tank.
我和查理(越共的蔑称)面对面
Me and Charlie, eyeball to eyeball. Yeah.
那才是战役
That's fucking combat.
那穿黑色长袍的家伙 酷哥
The man in the black pajamas, Dude.
是个该死的对手
Worthy fucking adversary.
谁穿着长袍 沃尔特? 闭嘴 唐尼
Who's in pajamas, Walter? Shut the fuck up, Donny.
我们有的只是...
Whereas what we have here,
那些把毛巾缠在头上的变态
a bunch of fig eaters wearing towels on their head,
为了弄翻那苏军的坦克
trying to find reverse on a Soviet tank.
- 这些对手不值得... - 嘿!
- This is not a worthy fucking adversary. - Hey!
这是说废话的日子吗?
What's this day-of-rest shit?
什么胡说八道的!
What's this bullshit?
我不在乎!对我来说不重要
I don't fucking care!It don't matter to Jesus.
但你们骗不了我
But you not fooling me, man.
你们也许能欺骗 那些比赛委员会的笨蛋
You might fool the fucks in the league office
但你骗不了我耶稣
but you don't fool Jesus.
那些都是胡话
It's Bush league psych-out stuff.
真可笑!
Laughable, man!
我本来可以 在周六收拾你们的
I would've fucked you in the ass Saturday.
现在改成下周三也无所谓
I'll fuck you in the ass next Wednesday instead.
你们周三有约了
You got a date Wednesday, baby!
他是个同性恋白鬼
He's cracking.
大亚洲的概念...
...the whole concept of age.
很多学者对此有争议
I mean, many learned men have disputed this
但在14世纪...
but in the 14th century, the Rambam...
他们总算成功了
Well, they finally did it.
他们毁了我的车
They killed my fucking car.
我们要钱 李波斯基
We want the money, Lebowski.
不然我们就杀了那女孩
Ja. Otherwise, we kill the girl.
你似乎忘记了我们的 交易了 李波斯基
Ja. It seems you have forgotten our little deal, Lebowski.
那女孩不在你们手上 混蛋
You don't have the fucking girl, dipshit.
我们知道的
We know you never did.
他们是纳粹吗 沃尔特?
Are these the Nazis, Walter?
不 唐尼 他们只是 些虚无主义者
No, Donny. These men are nihilists.
没什么要害怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of.
我们还是要钱
We don't care.
否则我们要对付你
We still want the money, Lebowski, or we fuck you up.
你们三个去死吧
Fuck you. Fuck the three of you. Cool it, Walter.
没有人质就没有赎金
No. Without a hostage, there is no ransom.
赎金就是这样的 这是规矩
That's what ransom is. Those are the fucking rules.
他女朋友献出了一只脚趾
His girlfriend gave up her toe.
她以为我们可以 拿到一百万的
She thought we could get $1 million.
- 这不公平 - 公平?
- It's not fair. - Fair?
那该死的家伙是谁? 你们这些娘娘腔的
Who's the fucking nihilists around here, you bunch of fucking crybabies?
沃尔特 冷静点
Cool it, Walter. Hey, look, pal.
根本就没什么钱
There never was any money.
老李波斯基给了 我一个空箱子
The big Lebowski gave me an empty briefcase,
你们去找他算帐吧
so take it up with him, man.
是啊 我还要拿回我的内裤
And I would like my undies back.
他们要伤害我们吗 沃尔特?
Are these guys gonna hurt us, Walter?
不 唐尼 他们都是懦夫
No, Donny. These men are cowards.
好!
Okay!
那我们拿走你们身上的钱 这样就扯平了
So we takes the money you have on you, and we calls it even.
去你的 不 沃尔特 来吧
Fuck you. Hey, no. Come on, Walter.
解决问题就算了
Come on, we're ending this thing cheap, man.
不 是我的东西就是我的 沃尔特
No. What's mine is mine. No, come on, Walter.
别耍花样 好了 我有...
No funny stuff. All right. All right.
差不多5块
No funny stuff. I got 4 bucks, almost 5.
- 我有18块 - 我的东西就是我的
- I got $1? - What's mine is mine.
我们要拿走你们的钱
We fuck you up, man!We takes the money!
过来拿啊
Come and get it.
我们要收拾你们 做给我看啊 混蛋
We fuck you up!Show me what you got, nihilists.
去你的 沃尔特 他有钢锯啊
I fuck you!Walter, come on. He's got a sword.
有9只脚趾的女人的男朋友
Fucking dipshit with a nine-toed woman!
去你的!去你的!
I fuck you!Fuck you!I fuck you!
别紧张 去你的!
Take it easy, man. I fuck you!
这里有4块
Take the $4. I fuck you!
去你的!
I fuck you!
我有一只保龄球
I'm gonna hit you with the fucking ball, man.
反犹的废物!
Hey, dickhead!Anti-Semite.
我要杀了你 我要杀了你
I fuck you in the ass!I fuck you in the ass!
去你的!
I fuck you!I fuck you!
有人倒下了 酷哥
We got a man down, Dude!
天啊 他们开枪了
Oh, God. They shot him, man.
不 酷哥 他们开枪射了唐尼?
He's not shot. No, Dude. Are you shot, Donny?
没有开枪
There weren't any shots fired. Huh?
这是心脏病发 找救护兵 酷哥
It's a heart attack. Call the medics, Dude.
我也想去 但我负伤了
I'd go myself, but I'm pumping blood, might pass out.
坚持住 伙计 你行的
Rest easy, good buddy. You're doing fine.
救援就到了
We got help choppering in.
嗨 先生们
Hello, gentlemen.
- 你们就是死者的亲属? - 是的
- You are the bereaved? - Yeah, man.
我是弗朗西斯.杜纳里 很高兴见到你们
Francis Donnelly, pleased to meet you.
杰弗里.李波斯基 沃尔特.索布查克
Jeff Lebowski. Walter Sobchak.
应该是酷哥
The Dude actually is...
- 什么? - 没什么
- Excuse me? - Oh, nothing.
我知道你们要带走骨灰
Yes. I understand you're taking away the remains?
是的
Yeah.
已经放进了骨灰罐
We have the urn.
这应该用信用卡结帐吧?
I assume this is credit card?
是的
Yeah.
这是什么?
What's this?
骨灰罐的钱
Now, that's for the urn.
没必要了 我们要将骨灰撒开
Don't need it. We're scattering the ashes.
好的
Yes. So we were informed.
但是...我们必须用一个
However, we must, of course, transmit the remains to you
容器转交给你们
in a receptacle.
要180美金啊
That's $180
这是我们最便宜的容器了
It is our most modestly priced receptacle.
- 我们能否...- 180美金?
- Well, can't we just... - $180?
最贵的可要3000呢
They range up to $3,000.
我们...可以租你们的吗?
We're... Can't we just rent it from you, you know?
先生 这里是殡仪馆 不是租借的地方
Sir, this is a mortuary not a rental house.
我们只是要将骨灰撒开!
We're scattering the fucking ashes!Walter, Walter.
别当我们是傻瓜!
Just because we're bereaved doesn't make us saps.
先生 请小声一点
Sir, please lower your voices.
你们有没有...其他东西给我们放骨灰的吗?
Man, don't you have, you know, something else we can put him in?
你知道
You know?
这是我们最便宜的容器了
That is our most modestly priced receptacle.
该死的!
God damn it!
这附近有超市吗?
Is there a Ralph's around here?
唐尼是一个保龄球好手 也是一个好人
Donny was a good bowler and a good man.
他是我们的同伴
He was one of us.
一个热爱保龄的男人
He was a man who loved the outdoors and bowling.
他喜欢冲浪 热爱南加州的海滩
And as a surfer he explored the beaches of Southern California
从圣荷拉一直到普里斯莫
from La Jolla to Leo Carrillo and up to Pismo.
他英年早逝
He died as so many young men of his generation, before his time.
真主 以你的智慧 你带走了他
In your wisdom, Lord, you took him,
正如你带走了其他年轻人
as you took so many bright, flowering young men
在科沙 在兰多
at Khe Sanh, at Lan Doc,
还有北越的364高地
at Hill 364.
那些年轻人献出了生命
These young men gave their lives,
唐尼也如此
and so did Donny.
热爱保龄球的唐尼
Donny, who loved bowling.
唐尼.卡拉波索斯
And so,Theodore Donald Kerabatsos,
根据我们所想到的 你最后的愿望
in accordance with what we think your dying wishes might well have been,
我们将你的骨灰
we commit your final mortal remains
投入太平洋的怀抱
to the bosom of the Pacific Ocean
这是你最喜爱的海洋
which you loved so well.
永别了 朋友
Good night, sweet prince.
该死的
Shit.
酷哥 对不起
Oh, shit, Dude. I'm sorry.
该死的大风 沃尔特
Goddamn wind. Fuck, god damn it, Walter!
你这个混蛋!酷哥 对不起
You fucking asshole!Shit, Dude. I'm sorry.
跟你一起什么事都倒透霉
Everything's a fucking travesty with you, man!
对不起 那是意外
I'm sorry. It was an accident.
那些越战的鬼话是什么?
What was that shit about Vietnam? Dude, I'm sorry.
为什么所有事情 都和越南拉上关系?
What the fuck does anything have to do with Vietnam?
你在说什么鬼话?
Dude, I'm sorry. What the fuck are you talking about?
酷哥 对不起
Dude, I'm sorry.
你...
Fucking...
去你的 沃尔特
Fuck, Walter.
酷哥 别说了
Come on, Dude.
去你的
Hey, fuck it, man.
我们去打保龄吧
Let's go bowling.
And when you're sittin' there
In your silk upholstered chair
Talkin' to some rich folks that you know
Well, I hope you don't see me
In my ragged company
O? but you know I could never be alone
2份苏打水 加里 祝你们明天好运
Two oat sodas, Gary. Right. Good luck tomorrow.
好的 谢谢 唐尼的事我很难过
Yeah, thanks, man. I was sorry to hear about Donny.
是啊
Oh, yeah. Well, you know,
世事难料 有时候你吃熊 有时候...
sometimes you eat the bear, and sometimes, you know...
嘿 你好
Hey, man.
你好啊 酷哥 我还想着能否再见到你
How do you do, Dude? I wondered if I'd see you again.
我没错过半决赛吧?
I wouldn't miss the semis.
最近怎么了?
Oh, yeah? How's things been going?
还是那样 有起有伏
Well, you know, strikes and gutters, ups and downs.
是啊
Sure. I got you. Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks, Gary.
我得回去了 保重
Well, take care, man. Gotta get back.
好的 酷哥 放轻松 好的
Sure. Take it easy, Dude. Oh, yeah.
我知道你会的
I know that you will.
当然了 没有什么酷哥迈不过的坎
Yeah. Well, the Dude abides.
沃尔特
Walter.
没有什么酷哥迈不过的坎
The Dude abides.
不知道你是否这样 但我从中得到安慰
I don't know about you, but I take comfort in that.
看到酷哥一切如常
It's good knowing he's out there,
这让人很高兴
the Dude, taking her easy for all us sinners.
希望他能打进决赛
I sure hope he makes the finals.
将对手打个落花流水
Well, that about does her.Wraps her all up.
酷哥和沃尔特的 状况似乎不错
Things seem to have worked out pretty good for the Dude and Walter.
这也是一个不错的故事 你说不是吗?
And it was a pretty good story, don't you think?
逗我笑弯了腰
Made me laugh to beat the band.
但也有泪
Parts anyway.
唐尼之死令我不忍
I didn't like seeing Donny go.
但我知道...一个小李波斯基 就要出现了
But then I happen to know that there's a little Lebowski on the way.
可悲的人类就是这样繁衍下去
I guess that's the way the whole darned human comedy keeps perpetuating itself
一代接一代
down through the generations.
就如西部的大马车...横跨大沙漠...
Westward the wagons, across the sands of time until we...
看看我 又开始长篇大论了
Oh, look at me. I'm rambling again.
希望你们喜欢这个故事
Well, I hope you folks enjoyed yourselves.
在保龄球场上再见
Catch you later on down the trail.
再给我一杯撒尔沙酒好吗?
Say, friend, you got any more of that good sarsaparilla?
w
ww
www
www.
www.H
www.HD
www.HDc
www.HDcm
www.HDcmc
www.HDcmct
www.HDcmct.
www.HDcmct.c
www.HDcmct.co
www.HDcmct.com
Take me down, little Susie
Take me down
I know you think you're the queen
Of the underground
Send me dead flowers every morning
Send me dead flowers by the mail
Send me dead flowers to my wedding
And I won't forget to put roses on your grave
No, I won't forget to put roses
On your grave
Bright light city gonna set my soul
Gonna set my soul on fire
Got a whole lot of money that's ready to burn
So get those stakes up higher
There's a thousand pretty women livin' out there
They're all livin' devil may care
And I'm just a devil with love to spare
So viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas with your neon flashing
And your one-arm bandits crashing
All those hopes down the drain
Viva Las Vegas turnin' day into nighttime
Night into daytime
If you see it once
You'll never be the same again
I'm gonna keep on keep on runnin'
If it costs me my very last dime
If I wind up broke